<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.2/eml.xsd"
packageId="47f16512-bf31-410f-b272-d151c996b2f6"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
xml:lang="en">

    <dataset>
            <alternateIdentifier>10.15468/3jnxf3</alternateIdentifier>
                <alternateIdentifier>13731</alternateIdentifier>
        <title>The Clements Checklist</title>
            <creator>
<organizationName>Cornell Lab of Ornithology</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>cornellbirds@cornell.edu</electronicMailAddress>            </creator>
            <metadataProvider>
            <individualName>
<givenName>Markus</givenName>                    <surName>Döring</surName>
            </individualName>
<organizationName>GBIF</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>mdoering@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>            </metadataProvider>
            <associatedParty>
<organizationName>Cornell Lab of Ornithology</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>cornellbirds@cornell.edu</electronicMailAddress>            <role>POINT_OF_CONTACT</role>
            </associatedParty>
            <pubDate>
                2021-08-14
            </pubDate>
        <language>ENGLISH</language>
            <abstract>
                    <para>The Clements Checklist of Birds of the World, 6th Edition was published and released by Cornell University Press in June 2007. The book was produced from a nearly completed manuscript left by James Clements upon his death in 2005.

The Cornell Lab of Ornithology has accepted the job of maintaining the ever-changing list of species, subspecies, English names, and approximate distributions, beginning with publication of the 6th Edition. Our procedures for accomplishing this ongoing task include using the considerable expertise of our research ornithologists on staff, aided enormously by input from knowledgeable professional and amateur cooperators worldwide. We invite input on known or suspected errors or updates at any time.

This website serves as the clearinghouse for keeping your Clements Checklist up to date. We will post all corrections once a year in August. At the same time, we’ll post updates to the taxonomy, scientific and English nomenclature, and range descriptions, to incorporate changes that have made their way into the literature and are generally accepted by the appropriate scientific body or community. In the future, we will also be posting a list of alternative English names.</para>
            </abstract>
            <intellectualRights>
                    <para>This work is licensed under a <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode"><citetitle>Creative Commons Attribution (CC-BY) 4.0 License</citetitle></ulink>.</para>
            </intellectualRights>
            <distribution scope="document">
                <online>
                    <url function="information">https://www.birds.cornell.edu/clementschecklist</url>
                </online>
            </distribution>

    </dataset>

    <additionalMetadata>
        <metadata>
            <gbif>
                <dateStamp>2023-08-28T14:20:49Z</dateStamp>
                <citation>Cornell Lab of Ornithology (2021). The Clements Checklist. Checklist dataset https://doi.org/10.15468/3jnxf3 accessed via GBIF.org on 2023-08-28.</citation>
                    <bibliography>
                <citation>2016 (Identification of the Larus canus complex). Dutch Birding 38: 1-64. Adriaens, P., and C. Gibbins. 2016. Identification of the Larus canus complex. Dutch Birding 38: 1-64</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Missing for 170 years—the rediscovery of Black-browed Babbler Malacocincla perspicillata on Borneo). BirdingASIA 34: 13-14. Akbar, P.G., T.W. Nugroho, M. Suranto, M.R. Fauzan, D. Ferdiansyah, J.S. Trisiyanto, and D.L. Yong. 2020. Missing for 170 years—the rediscovery of Black-browed Babbler Malacocincla perspicillata on Borneo. BirdingASIA 34: 13-14</citation>
                <citation>2012 (Convergent evolution of morphological and ecological traits in the open-habitat chat complex (Aves, Muscicapidae: Saxicolinae)). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 65: 35-45. Aliabadian, M., M. Kaboli, M.I. Förschler, V. Nijman, A. Chamani, A. Tillier, R. Prodon, E. Pasquet, P.G.P. Ericson, and D. Zuccon. 2012. Convergent evolution of morphological and ecological traits in the open-habitat chat complex (Aves, Muscicapidae: Saxicolinae). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 65: 35-45</citation>
                <citation>2003 (Pipits and wagtails). Princeton University Press, Princeton, New Jersey. Alström, P. and K. Mild. 2003. Pipits and wagtails. Princeton University Press, Princeton, New Jersey</citation>
                <citation>2021 (Mongolian Short‑toed Lark Calandrella dukhunensis, an overlooked East Asian species. J). Journal of Ornithology 162: 165–177. Alström, P., and G. Sundev. 2021. Mongolian Short‑toed Lark Calandrella dukhunensis, an overlooked East Asian species. Journal of Ornithology 162: 165–177</citation>
                <citation>2011a (Multilocus analysis of a taxonomically densely sampled dataset reveal extensive non-monophyly in the avian family Locustellidae). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 58: 513–526. Alström, P., S. Fregin, J.A Norman, P.G.P. Ericson, L. Christidis, and U. Olsson. 2011a. Multilocus analysis of a taxonomically densely sampled dataset reveal extensive non-monophyly in the avian family Locustellidae. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 58: 513–526</citation>
                <citation>2018b (Comprehensive molecular phylogeny of the grassbirds and allies (Locustellidae) reveals extensive non-monophyly of traditional genera, and a proposal for a new classification). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 127: 367–375. Alström, P., A. Cibois, M. Irestedt, D. Zuccon, M. Gelang, J. Fjeldså, M.J. Andersen, R.G. Moyle, E. Pasquet, and U. Olsson. 2018b. Comprehensive molecular phylogeny of the grassbirds and allies (Locustellidae) reveals extensive non-monophyly of traditional genera, and a proposal for a new classification. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 127: 367–375</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Multiple species within the Striated Prinia Prinia crinigera–Brown Prinia P. polychroa complex revealed through an integrative taxonomic approach). Ibis 162: 936–967. Alström, P., P.C. Rasmussen, G. Sangster, S. Dalvi, P.D. Round, R. Zhang, C.-T. Yao, M. Irestedt, H.L. Manh, F. Lei, and U. Olsson. 2020. Multiple species within the Striated Prinia Prinia crinigera–Brown Prinia P. polychroa complex revealed through an integrative taxonomic approach. Ibis 162: 936–967</citation>
                <citation>2021a (Multiple species delimitation approaches applied to the avian lark genus Alaudala). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 154: 106994. Alström, P., J. van Linschooten, P.F. Donald, G. Sundev, Z. Mohammadi, F. Ghorbani, A. Shafaeipour, A. van den Berg, M. Robb, M. Alibadian, C. Wei, F. Lei, B. Oxelman, and U. Olsson. 2021. Multiple species delimitation approaches applied to the avian lark genus Alaudala. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 154: 106994</citation>
                <citation>2021b (Morphology, vocalizations, and mitochondrial DNA suggest that the Graceful Prinia is two species). Ornithology 138: ukab014. Alström, P., P.C. Rasmussen, C. Xia, L. Zhang, C. Liu, J. Magnusson, A. Shafaeipour, and U. Olsson. 2021b. Morphology, vocalizations, and mitochondrial DNA suggest that the Graceful Prinia is two species. Ornithology 138: ukab014</citation>
                <citation>1957 (Check-list of North American birds. Fifth edition). American Ornithologists&apos; Union, Port City Press, Baltimore, Maryland. American Ornithologists&apos; Union. 1957. Check-list of North American birds. Fifth edition. American Ornithologists&apos; Union, Port City Press, Baltimore, Maryland</citation>
                <citation>2019 (Species limits and biogeography of Rhynchospiza sparrows). Journal of Ornithology 160: 973-991. Areta, J.I., E.A. Depino, S.A. Salvador, S.W. Cardiff, K. Epperly, and I. Holzmann. 2019. Species limits and biogeography of Rhynchospiza sparrows. Journal of Ornithology 160: 973-991</citation>
                <citation>2013 (Great Horned Owl (Bubo virginianus), version 2.0). In A.F. Poole (editor), The birds of North America. Cornell Lab of Ornithology, Ithaca, New York. Artuso, C., C.S. Houston, D.G. Smith, and C. Rohner. 2013. Great Horned Owl (Bubo virginianus), version 2.0. In A.F. Poole (editor), The birds of North America. Cornell Lab of Ornithology, Ithaca, New York</citation>
                <citation>2016 (The Yellow-green Bush-tanager is neither a bush-tanager nor a sparrow: molecular phylogenetics reveals that Chlorospingus flavovirens is a tanager (Aves: Passeriformes; Thraupidae)). Zootaxa 4136: 373–381. Avendaño, J., F.K. Barker, and C.D. Cadena. 2016. The Yellow-green Bush-tanager is neither a bush-tanager nor a sparrow: molecular phylogenetics reveals that Chlorospingus flavovirens is a tanager (Aves: Passeriformes; Thraupidae). Zootaxa 4136: 373–381</citation>
                <citation>2019 (Molecular systematics of the Amazonian endemic genus Hylexetastes (Aves: Dendrocolaptidae): taxonomic and conservation implications). Ibis 161:. Azuaje-Rodríguez, R.A., J.D. Weckstein, J.H. Dispoto, S. Patel, J.A. Cacioppo, J.M. Bates, S.M. Silva, and A. Aleixo. 2019. Molecular systematics of the Amazonian endemic genus Hylexetastes (Aves: Dendrocolaptidae): taxonomic and conservation implications. Ibis 161: xxx-xxx</citation>
                <citation>1987 (Taxonomic notes on Singing Quail (genus Dactylortyx) from western and southern Mexico). Occasional Papers of the Western Foundation of Vertebrate Zoology 4: 1‐6. Banks, R.C. 1987. Taxonomic notes on Singing Quail (genus Dactylortyx) from western and southern Mexico. Occasional Papers of the Western Foundation of Vertebrate Zoology 4: 1‐6</citation>
                <citation>2015 (New insights into New World biogeography: an integrated view from the phylogeny of blackbirds, cardinals, sparrows, tanagers, warblers, and allies). Auk 132: 333-348. Barker, F.K., K.J. Burns, J. Klicka, S.M. Lanyon, and I.J. Lovette. 2015. New insights into New World biogeography: an integrated view from the phylogeny of blackbirds, cardinals, sparrows, tanagers, warblers, and allies. Auk 132: 333-348</citation>
                <citation>2011 (Phylogeography of the Barred Owl (Strix varia): Species limits, multiple refugia, and range expansion). Auk 128:696–706. Barrowclough, G.F., J.G. Groth, K.J. Odom, and J.E. Lai. 2011. Phylogeography of the Barred Owl (Strix varia): Species limits, multiple refugia, and range expansion. Auk 128:696–706</citation>
                <citation>2016 (Birds of New Guinea: distribution, taxonomy, and systematics). Princeton University Press, Princeton, New Jersey. Beehler, B.M., and T.K. Pratt. 2016. Birds of New Guinea: distribution, taxonomy, and systematics. Princeton University Press, Princeton, New Jersey</citation>
                <citation>1971 (The land birds of Aldabra). Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B 260: 417-527. Benson, C.W., and M.J. Penny. 1971. The land birds of Aldabra. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B 260: 417-527</citation>
                <citation>2014 (A comprehensive multilocus phylogeny of the Neotropical cotingas (Cotingidae, Aves) with a comparative evolutionary analysis of breeding system and plumage dimorphism and a revised phylogenetc classification). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 81: 120-136. Berv, J.S., and R.O. Prum. 2014. A comprehensive multilocus phylogeny of the Neotropical cotingas (Cotingidae, Aves) with a comparative evolutionary analysis of breeding system and plumage dimorphism and a revised phylogenetc classification. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 81: 120-136</citation>
                <citation>1989 (A distributional survey of the birds of the Mexican state of Oaxaca.  Ornithological Monographs number 43). A distributional survey of the birds of the Mexican state of Oaxaca.  Ornithological Monographs number 43. Binford, L. C. 1989. A distributional survey of the birds of the Mexican state of Oaxaca.  Ornithological Monographs number 43</citation>
                <citation>2020 (A taxonomic revision of the Striated Grasswren Amytornis striatus complex (Aves: Maluridae) after analysis of phylogenetic and phenotypic data). Emu 120: 191-200. Black, A., G. Dolman, C.A. Wilson, C.D. Campbell, L. Pedler, and L. Joseph. 2020. A taxonomic revision of the Striated Grasswren Amytornis striatus complex (Aves: Maluridae) after analysis of phylogenetic and phenotypic data. Emu 120: 191-200</citation>
                <citation>1977 (Manual of Neotropical birds. Volume 1). University of Chicago Press, Chicago, Illinois. Blake, E.R. 1977. Manual of Neotropical birds. Volume 1. University of Chicago Press, Chicago, Illinois</citation>
                <citation>1961 (Variation in the qual-dove Geotrygon frenata). Fieldiana: Zoology 39: 567-572. Blake, E.R., G. Hoy, and F. Contino. 1961. Variation in the qual-dove Geotrygon frenata. Fieldiana: Zoology 39: 567-572</citation>
                <citation>2015 (Morphological variability and taxonomy of the Blue-winged Parrotlet Forpus xanthopterygius (Psittacidae)). Revista Brasileira de Ornitologia 23: 64-75. Bocalini, F., and L.F. Silverira. 2015. Morphological variability and taxonomy of the Blue-winged Parrotlet Forpus xanthopterygius (Psittacidae). Revista Brasileira de Ornitologia 23: 64-75</citation>
                <citation>2016a (Notes on the vocalizations of Rufous-winged Antwren (Herpsilochmus rufimarginatus)). HBW Alive Ornithological Note 50. In Handbook of the Birds of the World Alive. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona. Boesman, P. 2016a. Notes on the vocalizations of Rufous-winged Antwren (Herpsilochmus rufimarginatus). HBW Alive Ornithological Note 50. In Handbook of the Birds of the World Alive. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona</citation>
                <citation>2016b (Notes on the vocalizations of Sedge Wren (Cistothorus platensis)). HBW Alive Ornithological Note 285. In Handbook of the Birds of the World Alive. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona. Boesman, P. 2016b. Notes on the vocalizations of Sedge Wren (Cistothorus platensis). HBW Alive Ornithological Note 285. In Handbook of the Birds of the World Alive. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona</citation>
                <citation>2016c (Notes on the vocalizations of Narcissus Flycatcher (Ficedula narcissina)). HBW Alive Ornithological Note 329. In Handbook of the Birds of the World Alive. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona. Boesman, P. 2016c. Notes on the vocalizations of Narcissus Flycatcher (Ficedula narcissina). HBW Alive Ornithological Note 329. In Handbook of the Birds of the World Alive. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona</citation>
                <citation>2016d (Notes on the vocalizations of Greyish Saltator (Saltator coerulescens)). HBW Alive Ornithological Note 395. In Handbook of the Birds of the World Alive. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona. Boesman, P. 2016d. Notes on the vocalizations of Greyish Saltator (Saltator coerulescens). HBW Alive Ornithological Note 395. In Handbook of the Birds of the World Alive. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Further vocal evidence for treating the Bahama Nuthatch Sitta (pusilla) insularis as a species). Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 140: 393–403. Boesman, P., and N.J. Collar. 2020. Further vocal evidence for treating the Bahama Nuthatch Sitta (pusilla) insularis as a species. Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 140: 393–403</citation>
                <citation>2008 (A molecular phylogeny of the Sylvia cantillans complex: cryptic species within the Mediterranean basin). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 48: 461–472. Brambilla, M., S. Vitulano, F. Spina, N. Baccetti, G. Gargallo, E. Fabbri, F. Guidali, and E. Randi. 2008. A molecular phylogeny of the Sylvia cantillans complex: cryptic species within the Mediterranean basin. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 48: 461–472</citation>
                <citation>2009 (Birds of East Asia. China, Taiwan, Korea, Japan, and Russia). Princeton University Press, Princeton, New Jersey. Brazil, M. 2009. Birds of East Asia. China, Taiwan, Korea, Japan, and Russia. Princeton University Press, Princeton, New Jersey</citation>
                <citation>2005 (The influence of Pleistocene glacial refugia on tawny owl genetic diversity and phylogeography in western Europe). Molecular Ecology 14: 3077–3094. Brito, P.H. 2005. The influence of Pleistocene glacial refugia on tawny owl genetic diversity and phylogeography in western Europe. Molecular Ecology 14: 3077–3094</citation>
                <citation>1978 (An evaluation of the new species and subspecies proposed in Oberholser’s Bird Life of Texas). Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 91: 85‐122. Browning, M.R. 1978. An evaluation of the new species and subspecies proposed in Oberholser’s Bird Life of Texas. Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 91: 85‐122</citation>
                <citation>1990 (Taxa of North American birds described from 1957‐1987). Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 103: 432‐451. Browning, M.R. 1990. Taxa of North American birds described from 1957‐1987. Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 103: 432‐451</citation>
                <citation>2016 (Taxonomic revision of Saffron-billed Sparrow Arremon flavirostris Swainson, 1838 (Aves: Passerellidae) with comments on its holotype and type locality). Zootaxa 4178: 547-567. Buainain, N., G.R.R. Brito, D.H. Firme, D.M. Figueira, M.A. Raposo, and C. Pinto de Assis. 2016. Taxonomic revision of Saffron-billed Sparrow Arremon flavirostris Swainson, 1838 (Aves: Passerellidae) with comments on its holotype and type locality. Zootaxa 4178: 547-567</citation>
                <citation>2014 (Phylogenetics and diversification of tanagers (Passeriformes: Thraupidae), the largest radiation of Neotropical songbirds). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 75: 41-77. Burns, K.J., A.J. Shultz, P.O. Title, N.A. Mason, F.K. Barker, J. Klicka, S.M. Lanyon, and I.J. Lovette. 2014. Phylogenetics and diversification of tanagers (Passeriformes: Thraupidae), the largest radiation of Neotropical songbirds. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 75: 41-77</citation>
                <citation>2016 (A genus-level classification of the family Thraupidae (Class Aves: Order Passeriformes)). Zootaxa 4088: 329-354. Burns, K.J., P. Unitt, and N.A. Mason. 2016. A genus-level classification of the family Thraupidae (Class Aves: Order Passeriformes). Zootaxa 4088: 329-354</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Systematics, biogeography, and diversification of Scytalopus tapaculos (Rhinocryptidae), an enigmatic radiation of Neotropical montane birds). Auk 137: xxx-xxx. Cadena, C.D., A.M. Cuervo, L.N. Céspedes, G.A. Bravo, N. Krabbe, T.S. Schulenberg, G.E. Derryberry, L.F. Silveira, E.P. Derryberry, R.T. Brumfield, and J. Fjeldså. 2020. Systematics, biogeography, and diversification of Scytalopus tapaculos (Rhinocryptidae), an enigmatic radiation of Neotropical montane birds. Auk 137: xxx-xxx</citation>
                <citation>2018 (What makes the Sino-Himalayan mountains the major diversity hotspots for pheasants?). Journal of Biogeography 45: 640-651. Cai, T., J. Fjeldså, Y. Wu, S. Shao, Y. Chen, Q. Quan, X. Li, G. Song, Y. Qu, G. Qiao, and F. Lei. 2018. What makes the Sino-Himalayan mountains the major diversity hotspots for pheasants? Journal of Biogeography 45: 640-651</citation>
                <citation>2019 (Near-complete phylogeny and taxonomic revision of the world’s babblers (Aves: Passeriformes)). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 130: 346–356. Cai, T., A. Cibois, P. Alström, R.G. Moyle, J.D. Kennedy, S. Shao, R. Zhang, M. Irestedt, P.G.P. Ericson, M. Gelang, Y. Qu, F. Lei, and J. Fjeldså. 2019. Near-complete phylogeny and taxonomic revision of the world’s babblers (Aves: Passeriformes). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 130: 346–356</citation>
                <citation>2001 (Western Screech‐Owl (Megascops kennicottii)). In A. Poole and F. Gill (editors), The birds of North America. Number 597. Cornell Laboratory of Ornithology, Ithaca, New York. Cannings, R.J., and T. Angell. 2001. Western Screech‐Owl (Megascops kennicottii). A. Poole and F. Gill (editors), The birds of North America. Number 597. Cornell Laboratory of Ornithology, Ithaca, New York</citation>
                <citation>2016 (Phylogeography of the Vermilion Flycatcher species complex: multiple speciation events, shifts in migratory behavior, and an apparent extinction of a Galápagos-endemic bird species). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 102: 152–173. Carmi, O., C.C. Witt, A. Jaramillo, and J.P. Dumbacher. 2016. Phylogeography of the Vermilion Flycatcher species complex: multiple speciation events, shifts in migratory behavior, and an apparent extinction of a Galápagos-endemic bird species. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 102: 152–173</citation>
                <citation>2018 (Molecular systematics and biogeography of lowland antpittas (Aves, Grallariidae): the role of vicariance and dispersal in the diversification of a widespread Neotropical lineage). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 120: 375-389. Carneiro, L., G.A. Bravo, N. Aristizábal, A.M. Cuervo, and A. Aleixo. 2018. Molecular systematics and biogeography of lowland antpittas (Aves, Grallariidae): the role of vicariance and dispersal in the diversification of a widespread Neotropical lineage. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 120: 375-389</citation>
                <citation>2019 (Phenotypic similarity leads to taxonomic inconsistency: a revision of the lowland&apos;s antpittas). Zoologica Scripta 48: 46–56. Carneiro, L., G.A. Bravo, and A. Aleixo. 2019. Phenotypic similarity leads to taxonomic inconsistency: a revision of the lowland&apos;s antpittas. Zoologica Scripta 48: 46–56</citation>
                <citation>1994 (Family Odontophoridae (New World quails)). Pages. 412‐433 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and J. Sargatal (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 2. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona. Carroll, J.P. 1994. Family Odontophoridae (New World quails). Pages. 412‐433 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and J. Sargatal (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 2. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona</citation>
                <citation>2013 (Biogeography and evolutionary history of the Neotropical genus Saltator (Aves: Thraupini)). Journal of Biogeography 40: 2180–2190. Chaves, J.C., J.R. Hidalgo, and J. Klicka. 2013. Biogeography and evolutionary history of the Neotropical genus Saltator (Aves: Thraupini). Journal of Biogeography 40: 2180–2190</citation>
                <citation>2015 (Revival of the genus Tropicoperdix Blyth 1859 (Phasianidae, Aves) using multilocus sequence data). Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society 175: 429-438. Chen, D., Y. Liu, G.W.H. Davison, L. Dong, J. Chang, S. Gao, S.-H. Li, and Z. Zhang. 2015. Revival of the genus Tropicoperdix Blyth 1859 (Phasianidae, Aves) using multilocus sequence data. Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society 175: 429-438</citation>
                <citation>2018 (A simple strategy for recovering ultraconserved elements, exons, and introns from low coverage shotgun sequencing of museum specimens: placement of the partridge genus Tropicoperdix within the galliformes). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 129: 304-314. Chen, D., E.L. Braun, M. Forthman, R.T. Kimball, and Z. Zhang. 2018. A simple strategy for recovering ultraconserved elements, exons, and introns from low coverage shotgun sequencing of museum specimens: placement of the partridge genus Tropicoperdix within the galliformes. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 129: 304-314</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Disentangling the evolutionary history and biogeography of hill partridges (Phasianidae, Arborophila) from low coverage shotgun sequences). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 151: 106895. Chen, D., Y. Liu, G. Davison, D.L. Yong, S. Gao, J. Hu, S.-H. Li, and Z. Zhang. 2020. Disentangling the evolutionary history and biogeography of hill partridges (Phasianidae, Arborophila) from low coverage shotgun sequences. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 151: 106895</citation>
                <citation>1987 (A synopsis of the avifauna of China). Science Press, Beijing. Cheng, T.-h. 1987. A synopsis of the avifauna of China. Science Press, Beijing</citation>
                <citation>2019 (Sixtieth supplement to the American Ornithological Society&apos;s Check-list of North American birds). Auk 136: ukz042. Chesser, R.T., K.J. Burns, C. Cicero, J.L. Dunn, A.W. Kratter, I.J. Lovette, P.C. Rasmussen, J.V. Remsen, Jr., D.F. Stotz, and K. Winker. 2019. Sixtieth supplement to the American Ornithological Society&apos;s Check-list of North American birds. Auk 136: ukz042</citation>
                <citation>2018b (Molecular systematics of swifts of the genus Chaetura (Aves: Apodiformes: Apodidae)). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 128: 162-171. Chesser, R.T., H. Vaseghi, P.A. Hosner, L.M. Bergner, M.N. Cortes-Rodriguez, A.J. Welch, and C.T. Collins. 2018. Molecular systematics of swifts of the genus Chaetura (Aves: Apodiformes: Apodidae). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 128: 162-171</citation>
                <citation>2020a (Conservative plumage masks extraordinary genetic diversity in the Grallaria rufula (Rufous Antpitta) complex of the humid Andes). Auk 137: ukaa009. Chesser, R.T., M.L. Isler, A.M. Cuero, C.D. Cadena, S.C. Galen, L.M. Bergner, R.C. Fleischer, G.A. Bravo, D.F. Lane, and P.A. Hosner. 2020a Conservative plumage masks extraordinary genetic diversity in the Grallaria rufula (Rufous Antpitta) complex of the humid Andes. Auk 137: ukaa009</citation>
                <citation>2020b (Sixty-first Supplement to the American Ornithological Society’s Check-list of North American Birds). Auk 137: ukaa030. Chesser, R.T., S.M. Billerman, K.J. Burns, C. Cicero, J.L. Dunn, A.W. Kratter, I.J. Lovette, N.A. Mason, P.C. Rasmussen, J.V. Remsen, Jr., D.F. Stotz, and K. Winker. 2020b. Sixty-first Supplement to the American Ornithological Society’s Check-list of North American Birds. Auk 138: ukaa030</citation>
                <citation>2020c (A revised classification of the Xolmiini (Aves: Tyrannidae: Fluvicolinae), including a new genus for Muscisaxicola fluviatilis). Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 133: 35–48. Chesser, R.T., M.G. Harvey, R.T. Brumfield, and E.P. Derryberry. 2020c. A revised classification of the Xolmiini (Aves: Tyrannidae: Fluvicolinae), including a new genus for Muscisaxicola fluviatilis. Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 133: 35–48</citation>
                <citation>2021a (Addendum to the Sixty-first Supplement to the American Ornithological Society’s Check-list of North American Birds). Auk 138: ukaa074. Chesser, R.T., S.M. Billerman, K.J. Burns, C. Cicero, J.L. Dunn, A.W. Kratter, I.J. Lovette, N.A. Mason, P.C. Rasmussen, J.V. Remsen, Jr., D.F. Stotz, and K. Winker. 2021a. Addendum to the Sixty-first Supplement to the American Ornithological Society’s Check-list of North American Birds. Auk 138: ukaa074</citation>
                <citation>2021b (Sixty-second Supplement to the American Ornithological Society’s Check-list of North American Birds). Auk 138: ukab037. Chesser, R.T., S.M. Billerman, K.J. Burns, C. Cicero, J.L. Dunn, B.E. Hernández-Baños, A.W. Kratter, I.J. Lovette, N.A. Mason, P.C. Rasmussen, J.V. Remsen, Jr., D.F. Stotz, and K. Winker. 2021b. Sixty-second Supplement to the American Ornithological Society’s Check-list of North American Birds. Auk 138: ukab037</citation>
                <citation>2008 (Systematics and taxonomy of Australian birds). CSIRO Publishing, Melbourne. Christidis, L. and W.E. Boles. 2008. Systematics and taxonomy of Australian birds. CSIRO Publishing, Melbourne</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Behavioral, morphological, and ecological trait evolution in two clades of New World Sparrows (Aimophila and Peucaea, Passerellidae)). Peerj 8:e9249. Cicero, C., N.A. Mason, L. Benedict, and J.D. Rising. 2020. Behavioral, morphological, and ecological trait evolution in two clades of New World Sparrows (Aimophila and Peucaea, Passerellidae). Peerj 8:e9249</citation>
                <citation>1980 (Clancey, P.A. 1980. S.A.O.S. Checklist of southern African birds. Southern African Ornithological Society). Clancey, P.A. 1980. S.A.O.S. Checklist of southern African birds. Southern African Ornithological Society. Clancey, P.A. 1980. S.A.O.S. Checklist of southern African birds. Southern African Ornithological Society</citation>
                <citation>2001 (Family Trogonidae (trogons)). Pages 80-127 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and J. Sargatal (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 6. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona. Collar, N.J. 2001. Family Trogonidae (trogons). Pages 80-127 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and J. Sargatal (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 6. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona</citation>
                <citation>2005 (Family Turdidae (thrushes)). Pages 514-807 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and D.A. Christie (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 10. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona. Collar, N.J. 2005. Family Turdidae (thrushes). Pages 514-807 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and D.A. Christie (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 10. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona</citation>
                <citation>2019 (The taxonomy of certain Asio and Bubo owl species in Africa and Arabia). Bulletin of the African Bird Club 26: 155-169. Collar, N.J., and P. Boesman. 2019. The taxonomy of certain Asio and Bubo owl species in Africa and Arabia. Bulletin of the African Bird Club 26: 155-169</citation>
                <citation>2014 (The subspecies of Yellow-crested Cockatoo Cacatua sulphurea). Forktail 30: 23-27. Collar, N.J., and S.J. Marsden. 2014. The subspecies of Yellow-crested Cockatoo Cacatua sulphurea. Forktail 30: 23-27</citation>
                <citation>2007 (Family Timaliidae (babblers)). Pages 70-291 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and D.A. Christie (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 12. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona. Collar, N.J., and C. Robson. 2007. Family Timaliidae (babblers). Pages 70-291 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and D.A. Christie (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 12. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona</citation>
                <citation>1968 (Notes on the biology of Chapman&apos;s Swift Chaetura chapmani (Aves, Apodidae)). American Museum Novitates 2320. Collins, C.T. 1968. Notes on the biology of Chapman&apos;s Swift Chaetura chapmani (Aves, Apodidae). American Museum Novitates 2320</citation>
                <citation>2017 (When morphology is not reflected by molecular phylogeny: the case of three &apos;orange-billed terns&apos; Thalasseus maximus, Thalasseus bergii, and Thalasseus bengalensis (Charadriiformes: Laridae)). Biological Journal of the Linnean Society 121: 439–445. Collinson, J.M., P. Dufour, A.A. Hamza, Y. Lawrie, M. Elliott, C. Barlow, and P-A. Crochet. 2017. When morphology is not reflected by molecular phylogeny: the case of three &apos;orange-billed terns&apos; Thalasseus maximus, Thalasseus bergii, and Thalasseus bengalensis (Charadriiformes: Laridae). Biological Journal of the Linnean Society 121: 439–445</citation>
                <citation>2017 (Vocal variation and species limits in the Sclerurus mexicanus complex). Wilson Journal of Ornithology 129: 13-24. Cooper, J.C., and A.M. Cuervo. 2017. Vocal variation and species limits in the Sclerurus mexicanus complex. Wilson Journal of Ornithology 129: 13-24</citation>
                <citation>2014 (Niche divergence promotes rapid diversification of East African sky island white‐eyes (Aves: Zosteropidae)). Molecular Ecology 23: 4103-4118. Cox, S.C., R.P. Prys‐Jones, J.C. Habel, B.A. Amakobe, and J.J. Day. 2014. Niche divergence promotes rapid diversification of East African sky island white‐eyes (Aves: Zosteropidae). Molecular Ecology 23: 4103-4118</citation>
                <citation>1985 (Handbook of the birds of Europe, the Middle East, and North Africa. The birds of the Western Palearctic. Volume IV). Oxford University Press, New York and Oxford, United Kingdom. Cramp, S. (chief editor). 1985. Handbook of the birds of Europe, the Middle East, and North Africa. The birds of the Western Palearctic. Volume IV. Oxford University Press, New York and Oxford, United Kingdom</citation>
                <citation>1994 (Handbook of the birds of Europe, the Middle East, and North Africa. The birds of the Western Palearctic. Volume 8). Oxford University Press, New York and Oxford, United Kingdom. Cramp, S., and C.M. Perrins (editors). 1994. Handbook of the birds of Europe, the Middle East, and North Africa. The birds of the Western Palearctic. Volume 8. Oxford University Press, New York and Oxford, United Kingdom</citation>
                <citation>1994b (Handbook of the birds of Europe, the Middle East, and North Africa. The birds of the Western Palearctic. Volume 9). Oxford University Press, New York and Oxford, United Kingdom. Cramp, S., and C.M. Perrins (editors). 1994b. Handbook of the birds of Europe, the Middle East, and North Africa. The birds of the Western Palearctic. Volume 8. Oxford University Press, New York and Oxford, United Kingdom</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Resolving nomenclatural ‘confusion’ vis-à-vis Latham’s Francolin (Francolinus/Peliperdix/Afrocolinus lathami) and the ‘Red-tailed’ francolins (Francolinus/Ortygornis/Peliperdix spp.)). Ostrich 91: 134-136. Crowe, T.M., T.G. Mandiwana-Neudani,  D.B. Donsker, R.C.K. Bowie, and R.M. Little. 2020. Resolving nomenclatural ‘confusion’ vis-à-vis Latham’s Francolin (Francolinus/Peliperdix/Afrocolinus lathami) and the ‘Red-tailed’ francolins (Francolinus/Ortygornis/Peliperdix spp.). Ostrich 91: 134-136</citation>
                <citation>2013 (Taxonomia e bBiogeografia da especie politípica Herpsilochmus rufimarginatus (Temminck, 1822) (Aves: Thamnophilidae)). Unpublished thesis. Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Norte, Natal, Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil. da Silva, M. 2013. Taxonomia e bBiogeografia da especie politípica Herpsilochmus rufimarginatus (Temminck, 1822) (Aves: Thamnophilidae). Unpublished thesis. Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Norte, Natal, Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil</citation>
                <citation>2016 (Molecular systematics of the New World screech-owls (Megascops: Aves, Strigidae): biogeographic and taxonomic implications). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 94: 626-634. Dantas, S.M., J.D. Weckstein, J.M. Bates, N.K. Krabbe, C.D. Cadena, M.B. Robbins, E. Valderrama, and A. Aleixo. 2016. Molecular systematics of the New World screech-owls (Megascops: Aves, Strigidae): biogeographic and taxonomic implications. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 94: 626-634</citation>
                <citation>2017 (Addendum to Kirwan et al. (2016, Zootaxa 4121(1): 89–94)). Zootaxa 4216: 299–300. David, N., S.M.S. Gregory, G.M. Kirwan, J.A. Jobling, F.D. Steinheimer, and G.R.R. Brito. 2017. Addendum to Kirwan et al. (2016, Zootaxa 4121(1): 89–94). Zootaxa 4216: 299–300</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Reasserting the valid name of the Curl-crested Aracari (Aves, Ramphastidae): Pteroglossus beauharnaisii Wagler, 1831). Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 77:70-75. David, N., R. Wright, A. Elliott, and T.V.V. Costa. 2020. Reasserting the valid name of the Curl-crested Aracari (Aves, Ramphastidae): Pteroglossus beauharnaisii Wagler, 1831. Bulletin of Zoological Nomenclature 77:70-75</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Species rank for Rheinardia ocellata nigrescens (Phasianidae)). Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 140: 182-194. Davison, G.W.H., P. Boesman, N.J. Collar, and C.L. Puan. 2020. Species rank for Rheinardia ocellata nigrescens (Phasianidae). Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 140: 182-194</citation>
                <citation>2001 (Family Coliidae (mousebirds)). Pages 60-77 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and J. Sargatal (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 6. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona. de Juana, E. 2001. Family Coliidae (mousebirds). Pages 60-77 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and J. Sargatal (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 6. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona</citation>
                <citation>1963 (Checklist of the birds of Thailand). Bulletin of the United States National Museum 226. Deignan, H.G. 1963. Checklist of the birds of Thailand. Bulletin of the United States National Museum 226</citation>
                <citation>2014 (HBW and BirdLife International illustrated checklist of the birds of the world. Volume 1). Lynx Edicions, Barcelona. del Hoyo, J., and N.J. Collar. 2014. HBW and BirdLife International illustrated checklist of the birds of the world. Volume 1. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona</citation>
                <citation>2019 (Subspecies discrimination on the basis of acoustic signals: a playback experiment in a Neotropical songbird). Animal Behaviour 157: 77-85. Demko, A.D., J.R. Sosa-López, and D.J. Mennill. 2019. Subspecies discrimination on the basis of acoustic signals: a playback experiment in a Neotropical songbird. Animal Behaviour 157: 77-85</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Divergence in plumage, voice, and morphology indicates speciation in Rufous-capped Warblers (Basileuterus rufifrons)). Auk 137: ukaa029. Demko, A.D., J.R. Sosa-López, R.K. Simpson, S.M. Doucet, and D.J. Mennill. 2020. Divergence in plumage, voice, and morphology indicates speciation in
Rufous-capped Warblers (Basileuterus rufifrons). Auk 137: ukaa029</citation>
                <citation>2011 (Lineage diversification and morphological evolution in a large-scale continental radiation: the Neotropical ovenbirds and woodcreepers (Aves: Furnariidae)). Evolution 65: 2973–2986. Derryberry, E.P., S. Claramunt, G.Derryberry, R.T. Chesser, J. Cracraft, A. Aleixo, J. Pérez-Emán, J. V. Remsen, Jr., and R.T. Brumfield. 2011. Lineage diversification and morphological evolution in a large-scale continental radiation: the Neotropical ovenbirds and woodcreepers (Aves: Furnariidae). Evolution 65: 2973–2986</citation>
                <citation>1981 (Preliminary review of the Clay-coloured Robin Turdus grayi with redesignation of the type locality of the nominate form and description of a new subspecies). Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 101: 285-289. Dickerman, R.W. 1981. Preliminary review of the Clay-coloured Robin Turdus grayi with redesignation of the type locality of the nominate form and description of a new subspecies. Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 101: 285-289</citation>
                <citation>1993 (On the validity of Ceyx (Myioceyx) leconti ruficeps). Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 113: 255‐257. Dickerman, R.W. 1993. On the validity of Ceyx (Myioceyx) leconti ruficeps. Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 113: 255‐257</citation>
                <citation>1996 (The Prince of Wales Spruce Grouse: a new subspecies from southeastern Alaska). Western Birds 27: 41-47. Dickerman, R.W., and J. Gustafson. 1996. The Prince of Wales Spruce Grouse: a new subspecies from southeastern Alaska. Western Birds 27: 41-47</citation>
                <citation>2003 (The Howard &amp; Moore complete checklist of the birds of the world. Third edition). Princeton University Press, Princeton, New Jersey. Dickinson, E.C. (editor). 2003. The Howard &amp; Moore complete checklist of the birds of the world. Third edition. Princeton University Press, Princeton, New Jersey</citation>
                <citation>2014 (The Howard &amp; Moore complete checklist of the birds of the world. Fourth edition. Volume 2). Aves Press, Eastbourne, United Kingdom. Dickinson, E.C., and L. Christidis. 2014. The Howard &amp; Moore complete checklist of the birds of the world. Fourth edition. Volume 2. Aves Press, Eastbourne, United Kingdom</citation>
                <citation>2001 (Systematic notes on Asian birds. 11. A preliminary review of the Alaudidae). Zoologische Verhandeligen 335: 61-84. Dickinson, E.C., and R.W.R.J. Dekker. 2001. Systematic notes on Asian birds. 11. A preliminary review of the Alaudidae. Zoologische Verhandeligen 335: 61-84</citation>
                <citation>2002 (Systematic notes on Asian Birds. 22. A preliminary review of the Campephagidae). Zoologische Verhandeligen 340: 7-30. Dickinson, E.C., and R.W.R.J. Dekker. 2002. Systematic notes on Asian Birds. 22. A preliminary review of the Campephagidae. Zoologische Verhandeligen 340: 7-30</citation>
                <citation>2013 (The Howard &amp; Moore complete checklist of the birds of the world. Fourth edition. Volume 1). Aves Press, Eastbourne, United Kingdom. Dickinson, E.C., and J.V. Remsen, Jr. (editors). 2013. The Howard &amp; Moore complete checklist of the birds of the world. Fourth edition. Volume 1. Aves Press, Eastbourne, United Kingdom</citation>
                <citation>1991 (The birds of the Philippines. An annotated check-list. British Ornithologists&apos; Union Check-list number 12). British Ornithologists&apos; Union, London. Dickinson, E.C., R.S. Kennedy, and K.C. Parkes. 1991. The birds of the Philippines. An annotated check-list. British Ornithologists&apos; Union Check-list number 12. British Ornithologists&apos; Union, London</citation>
                <citation>2001b (Systematic notes on Asian birds. 19. Type material from Japan in the Natural History Museum, Tring, United Kingdom). Zoologische Verhandelingen 335: 215‐228. Dickinson, E.C., H. Morioka, and M. Walters. 2001. Systematic notes on Asian birds. 19. Type material from Japan in the Natural History Museum, Tring, United Kingdom. Zoologische Verhandelingen 335: 215‐228</citation>
                <citation>2016 (Revision of the status of bird species occurring or reported in Colombia 2016 and assessment of BirdLife International&apos;s new parrot taxonomy). Conservación Colombiana 24: 12-36. Donegan, T., J.C. Verhelst, T. Ellery, O. Cortés-Herrera, and P. Salaman. 2016. Revision of the status of bird species occurring or reported in Colombia 2016 and assessment of BirdLife International&apos;s new parrot taxonomy. Conservación Colombiana 24: 12-36</citation>
                <citation>2015, (Taxonomy of the Narcissus Flycatcher Ficedula narcissina complex: an integrative approach using morphological, bioacoustic and multilocus DNA data). Ibis 157: 312–325. Dong, L., M. Wei, P. Alström, X. Huang, U. Olsson, Y. Shigeta, Y. Zhang, and G. Zheng. 2015. Taxonomy of the Narcissus Flycatcher Ficedula narcissina complex: an integrative approach using morphological, bioacoustic and multilocus DNA data. Ibis 157: 312–325</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Strict allopatric speciation of sky island Pyrrhula erythaca species complex). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 153: 106941. Dong, F., S.-H. Li, C.-C. Chiu, L. Dong, C.-T. Yao, and X.-J. Yang. 2020. Strict allopatric speciation of sky island Pyrrhula erythaca species complex. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 153: 106941</citation>
                <citation>1999 (A taxonomic study of Crested Caracaras (Falconidae)). Wilson Bulletin 111: 330–339. Dove, C.J., and R.C. Banks. 1999. A taxonomic study of Crested Caracaras (Falconidae). Wilson Bulletin 111: 330–339</citation>
                <citation>2008 (The birds of Zambia). Tauraco Press and Aves, Liège, Belgium. Dowsett, R.J., D.R. Aspinwall, and F. Dowsett‐Lemaire. 2008. The birds of Zambia. Tauraco Press and Aves, Liège, Belgium</citation>
                <citation>2006 (The birds of Malawi: an atlas and handbook). Tauraco Press and Aves, Liège, Belgium. Dowsett‐Lemaire, F., and R.J. Dowsett. 2006. The birds of Malawi: an atlas and handbook. Tauraco Press and Aves, Liège, Belgium</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Identification of American Royal Tern and African Royal Tern based on photographs and sound-recordings). Dutch Birding 42: 1–24. Dufour, P., and P.-A. Crochet. 2020. Identification of American Royal Tern and African Royal Tern based on photographs and sound-recordings. Dutch Birding 42: 1–24</citation>
                <citation>2011 (Birds of Melanesia. The Bismarcks, Solomons, Vanuatu and New Caledonia). Christopher Helm, London. Dutson, G. 2011. Birds of Melanesia. The Bismarcks, Solomons, Vanuatu and New Caledonia. Christopher Helm, London</citation>
                <citation>2016 (Birds of the Indonesian Archipelago: Greater Sundas and Wallacea). Lynx Edicions, Barcelona. Eaton, J.A., B. van Balen, N.W. Brickle, and F.E. Rheindt. 2016. Birds of the Indonesian Archipelago: Greater Sundas and Wallacea. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona</citation>
                <citation>2006 (Systematic notes on Asian birds. 49. A preliminary review of the Aegithalidae, Remizidae and Paridae). Zoologische Mededelingen 80: 1-63. Eck, S., and J. Martens. 2006. Systematic notes on Asian birds. 49. A preliminary review of the Aegithalidae, Remizidae and Paridae. Zoologische Mededelingen 80: 1-63</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Appendix 2. Differences in nomenclature: selected cases where world lists use different names/spellings). Pages 853-859 in J. del Hoyo (editor), All the birds of the world. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona. Elliott, A. 2020. Appendix 2. Differences in nomenclature: selected cases where world lists use different names/spellings. Pages 853-859 in J. del Hoyo (editor), All the birds of the world. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona</citation>
                <citation>1993 (Variation géographique de Cursorius cinctus (Heuglin, 1863), Aves: Glareolidae). Bonner zoologische Beiträge 44: 165-192. Erard, C., G. Hémery, and E. Pasquet. 1993. Variation géographique de Cursorius cinctus (Heuglin, 1863), Aves: Glareolidae. Bonner zoologische Beiträge 44: 165-192</citation>
                <citation>2018 (Morphological evidence for the taxonomic status of the Bridges’s Guan, Penelope bridgesi, with comments on the validity of P. obscura bronzina (Aves: Cracidae)). Zoologia 35: e12993. Evangelista-Vargas, O.D., and L.F. Silveira. 2018. Morphological evidence for the taxonomic status of the Bridges’s Guan, Penelope bridgesi, with comments on the validity of P. obscura bronzina (Aves: Cracidae). Zoologia 35: e12993</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Phylogeography of the iconic Australian red-tailed black-cockatoo (Calyptorhynchus banksii) and implications for its conservation). Heredity 125: 85–100. Ewart, K.M., N. Lo, R. Ogden, L. Joseph, S.Y.W. Ho, G.J. Frankham, M.D.B. Eldridge, R. Schodde, and R.N. Johnson. 2020. Phylogeography of the iconic Australian red-tailed black-cockatoo (Calyptorhynchus banksii) and implications for its conservation. Heredity 125: 85–100</citation>
                <citation>2008 (Evolutionary ecological genetics of some Neotropical birds). Ph.D. dissertation, University of Alaska Fairbanks, Fairbanks, Alaska. Miller, M.J. 2008. Evolutionary ecological genetics of some Neotropical birds. Ph.D. dissertation, University of Alaska Fairbanks, Fairbanks, Alaska</citation>
                <citation>2019 (A reappraisal of Schouteden’s Swift Schoutedenapus schoutedeni). Bulletin of the African Bird Club 26: 38-57. Fishpool, L.D.C. 2019. A reappraisal of Schouteden’s Swift Schoutedenapus schoutedeni. Bulletin of the African Bird Club 26: 38-57</citation>
                <citation>2005 (Family Pycnonotidae (bulbuls). Pages 124-250 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and D.A. Christie (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 10). Lynx Edicions, Barcelona. Fishpool, L.D.C., and J.A. Tobias. 2005. Family Pycnonotidae (bulbuls). Pages 124-250 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and D.A. Christie (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 10. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona</citation>
                <citation>1983 (Geographic variation in the Andean Coot Fulica ardesiaca). Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 103: 18‐22. Fjeldså, J. 1983. Geographic variation in the Andean Coot Fulica ardesiaca. Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 103: 18‐22</citation>
                <citation>2018 (Rapid expansion and diversification into new niche space by fluvicoline flycatchers). Journal of Avian Biology 49: jav-01661. Fjeldså, J., J.I. Ohlson, H. Batalha-Filho, P.G.P. Ericson, and M. Irestedt. 2018. Rapid expansion and diversification into new niche space by fluvicoline flycatchers. Journal of Avian Biology 49: jav-01661</citation>
                <citation>2021 (Description of two new Cisticola species endemic to the marshes of the Kilombero floodplain of southwestern Tanzania). Ibis 163. Fjeldså, J., L. Dinesen, O.R. Davies, M. Irestedt, N.K. Krabbe, L.A. Hansen, and R.C.K. Bowie. 2021. Description of two new Cisticola species endemic to the marshes of the Kilombero floodplain of southwestern Tanzania. Ibis 163</citation>
                <citation>2015 (Reprising the taxonomy of Cyprus Scops Owl Otus (scops) cyprius, a neglected island endemic). Zootaxa 4040: 301–316. Flint, P., D. Whaley, G.M. Kirwan, M. Charalambides, M. Schwiezer, and M. Wink. 2015. Reprising the taxonomy of Cyprus Scops Owl Otus (scops) cyprius, a neglected island endemic. Zootaxa 4040: 301–316</citation>
                <citation>2008a (A substitute name for Celeus lugubris castaneus Olrog). Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 128: 69‐70. Fraga, R.M., and E.C. Dickinson. 2008b. A substitute name for Celeus lugubris castaneus Olrog. Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 128: 69‐70</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Species limits in the Tawny-crowned Pygmy-tyrant Euscarthmus meloryphus complex (Aves: Passeriformes: Tyrannidae)). Zootaxa 4809: 475-495. Franz, I., D.J. Alvares, and M. Borges-Martins. 2020. Species limits in the Tawny-crowned Pygmy-tyrant Euscarthmus meloryphus complex (Aves: Passeriformes: Tyrannidae). Zootaxa 4809: 475-495</citation>
                <citation>2017 (Using song playback experiments to measure species recognition between geographically isolated populations: a comparison with acoustic trait analyses). Auk 134: 857-870. Freeman, B.G., and G.A. Montogomery. 2017. Using song playback experiments to measure species recognition between geographically isolated populations: a comparison with acoustic trait analyses. Auk 134: 857-870</citation>
                <citation>2012b (Molecular systematics of the caracaras and allies (Falconidae: Polyborinae) inferred from mitochondrial and nuclear sequence data). Ibis 154: 520-532. Fuchs, J., J.A. Johnson, and D.P. Mindell. 2012b. Molecular systematics of the caracaras and allies (Falconidae: Polyborinae) inferred from mitochondrial and nuclear sequence data. Ibis 154: 520-532</citation>
                <citation>2015 (The complex phylogeography of the Indo-Malayan Alophoixus bulbuls with the description of a putative new ring species complex). Fuchs, J., P.G.P. Ericson, C. Bonillo, A. Couloux, and E. Pasquet. 2015. The complex phylogeography of the Indo-Malayan Alophoixus bulbuls with the description of a putative new ring species complex. Molecular Ecology 24: 5460-5474. Fuchs, J., P.G.P. Ericson, C. Bonillo, A. Couloux, and E. Pasquet. 2015. The complex phylogeography of the Indo-Malayan Alophoixus bulbuls with the description of a putative new ring species complex. Molecular Ecology 24: 5460-5474</citation>
                <citation>2019 (Miocene diversification of an open‐habitat predatorial passerine radiation, the shrikes (Aves: Passeriformes: Laniidae)). Zoologica Scripta 48: 571-588. Fuchs, J., P. Alström, R. Yosef, and U. Olsson. 2019. Miocene diversification of an open‐habitat predatorial passerine radiation, the shrikes (Aves: Passeriformes: Laniidae). Zoologica Scripta 48: 571-588</citation>
                <citation>2021 (Trait-dependent dispersal in rails (Aves: Rallidae): historical biogeography of a cosmopolitan bird clade). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 159: 107106. Garcia-R, J.C., and N.J. Matzke. 2021. Trait-dependent dispersal in rails (Aves: Rallidae): historical biogeography of a cosmopolitan bird clade. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 159: 107106</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Phylogenomic reconstruction sheds light on new relationships and timescale of rails (Aves: Rallidae) evolution). Diversity 12: 70. Garcia-R, J.C., E.M. Lemmon, A.R. Lemmon, and N. French. 2020. Phylogenomic reconstruction sheds light on new relationships and timescale of rails (Aves: Rallidae) evolution. Diversity 12: 70</citation>
                <citation>2003 (The taxonomic status of the Puerto Rican Bullfinch (Loxigilla portoricensis) (Emberizidae) in Puerto Rico and St. Kitts). Ornitología Neotropical 14: 91–98. Garrido, O.H., and J.W. Wiley. 2003. The taxonomic status of the Puerto Rican Bullfinch (Loxigilla portoricensis) (Emberizidae) in Puerto Rico and St. Kitts. Ornitología Neotropical 14: 91–98</citation>
                <citation>1997 (Birds of Liberia). Yale University Press,  New Haven, Connecticut, and London. Gatter, W., 1997. Birds of Liberia. Yale University Press,  New Haven, Connecticut, and London</citation>
                <citation>2009 (Phylogeny of babblers (Aves, Passeriformes): major lineages, family limits and classification). Zoologica Scripta 38: 225-236. Gelang, M., A. Cibois, E. Pasquet, U. Olsson, P. Alström and P.G.P. Ericson. 2009. Phylogeny of babblers (Aves, Passeriformes): major lineages, family limits and classification. Zoologica Scripta 38: 225-236</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Densely sampled phylogenetic analyses of the Lesser Short-toed Lark (Alaudala rufescens) — Sand Lark (A. raytal) species complex (Aves, Passeriformes) reveal cryptic diversity). Zoologica Scripta 49: 427–439. Ghorbani, F., M. Aliabadian, R. Zhang, M. Irestedt, Y. Hao, G. Sundev, F. Lei, M. Ma, U. Olsson, and P. Alström. 2020. Densely sampled phylogenetic analyses of the Lesser Short-toed Lark (Alaudala rufescens) — Sand Lark (A. raytal) species complex (Aves, Passeriformes) reveal cryptic diversity. Zoologica Scripta 49: 427–439</citation>
                <citation>2010 (Checklist of the birds of New Zealand). Te Papa Press and the Ornithological Society of New Zealand, Wellington, New Zealand. Gill, B.J., B.D. Bell, C.K. Chambers, D.G. Medway, R.L. Palma, R.P. Scofield, A.J.D. Tennyson, and T.H. Worthy (Checklist Committee, Ornithological Society of New Zealand). 2010. Checklist of the birds of New Zealand. Te Papa Press and the Ornithological Society of New Zealand, Wellington, New Zealand</citation>
                <citation>2021 (IOC World Bird List v 11.2).  Gill, F., D. Donsker, and P. Rasmussen (editors). 2021. IOC World Bird List v 11.2</citation>
                <citation>1965 (A systematic study of the terrestrial birds of the Tres Marias Islands, Mexico). Postilla 90. Grant, P.R. 1965. A systematic study of the terrestrial birds of the Tres Marias Islands, Mexico. Postilla 90</citation>
                <citation>1990 (A new subspecies of Diglossa gloriosissima (Aves: Thraupinae) from the Western Andes of Colombia). Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 103: 962-965. Graves, G.R. 1990. A new subspecies of Diglossa gloriosissima (Aves: Thraupinae) from the Western Andes of Colombia. Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 103: 962-965</citation>
                <citation>2012 (An assessment of three little-noticed papers on avian nomenclature by G. N. Kashin during 1978–1982). Zootaxa 3340: 44-58. Gregory, S.M.S., and E.C. Dickinson. 2012. An assessment of three little-noticed papers on avian nomenclature by G. N. Kashin during 1978–1982. Zootaxa 3340: 44-58</citation>
                <citation>2017 (Bioacoustic and multi-locus DNA data of Ninox owls support high incidence of extinction and recolonisation on small, low-lying islands across Wallacea). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 109: 246–258. Gwee, C.Y., L. Christidis, J.A. Eaton, J.A. Norman, C.R. Trainor, P. Verbelen, and F.E. Rheindt. 2017. Bioacoustic and multi-locus DNA data of Ninox owls support high incidence of extinction and recolonisation on small, low-lying islands across Wallacea. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 109: 246–258</citation>
                <citation>2019a (Cryptic diversity in Cyornis (Aves: Muscicapidae) jungle-flycatchers flagged by simple bioacoustic approaches). Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society in press. Gwee, C.Y., J.A. Eaton, K.M. Garg, P. Alström, S. Van Balen, R.O. Hutchinson, D.M. Prawiradilaga, M.H. Le, and F.E. Rheindt. 2019. Cryptic diversity in Cyornis (Aves: Muscicapidae) jungle-flycatchers flagged by simple bioacoustic approaches. Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society 186: 725-741</citation>
                <citation>2019b (Species delimitation within the Glaucidium brodiei owlet complex using bioacoustic tools). Avian Research 10: 36. Gwee, C.Y., J.A. Eaton, E.Y.X. Ng, and F.E. Rheindt. 2019b. Species delimitation within the Glaucidium brodiei owlet complex using bioacoustic tools. Avian Research 10: 36</citation>
                <citation>2021 (The interplay of colour and bioacoustic traits in the differentiation of a Southeast Asian songbird complex). Molecular Ecology 30: 297-309. Gwee, C.Y., Q.L. Lee, S.P. Mahood, H.L. Manh, R. Tizard, K. Eiamampai, P.D. Round, and F.E. Rheindt. 2021. The interplay of colour and bioacoustic traits in the differentiation of a Southeast Asian songbird complex. Molecular Ecology 30: 297-309</citation>
                <citation>2011 (Long-term isolation of a highly mobile seabird on the Galapagos). Proceedings of the Royal Society B 278: 817–825. Hailer, F., E.A. Schreiber, J.M. Miller, I.I. Levin, P.G. Parker, R.T. Chesser, and R.C. Fleischer. 2011. Long-term isolation of a highly mobile seabird on the Galapagos. Proceedings of the Royal Society B 278: 817–825</citation>
                <citation>2017 (Restoring the species status of Catharus maculatus (Aves: Turdidae), a secretive Andean thrush, with a critique of the yardstick approach to species delimitation). Zootaxa 4276: 387–404. Halley, M.R., J.C. Klicka, P.R.S. Clee, and J.D. Weckstein. 2017. Restoring the species status of Catharus maculatus (Aves: Turdidae), a secretive Andean thrush, with a critique of the yardstick approach to species delimitation. Zootaxa 4276: 387–404</citation>
                <citation>2020 (The evolution of a tropical biodiversity hotspot). Science 370: 1343-1348. Harvey, M.G., G.A. Bravo, S. Claramunt, A.M. Cuervo, G.E. Derryberry, J. Battilana, G.F. Seeholzer, J.S. McKay, B.C. O&apos;Meara, B.C. Faircloth, S.V. Edwards, J. Pérez-Emán, R.G. Moyle, F.H. Sheldon, A. Aleixo, B.T. Smith, R.T. Chesser, L.F. Silveira, J. Cracraft, R.T. Brumfield, and E.P. Derryberry. 2020. The evolution of a tropical biodiversity hotspot. Science 370: 1343-1348</citation>
                <citation>2004 (Grand Bahama&apos;s Brown-headed Nuthatch: a distinct and endangered species). Bahamas Journal of Science 12: 21–28. Hayes, W.K., R.X. Barry, Z. McKenzie, and P. Barry. 2004. Grand Bahama&apos;s Brown-headed Nuthatch: a distinct and endangered species. Bahamas Journal of Science 12: 21–28</citation>
                <citation>1948b (Catalogue of birds of the Americas. Part I, number 3). Field Museum of Natural History Zoological Series volume 13, part 1, number 3. Hellmayr, C.E., and B. Conover. 1948b. Catalogue of birds of the Americas. Part I, number 3. Field Museum of Natural History Zoological Series volume 13, part 1, number 3</citation>
                <citation>1949 (Catalogue of birds of the Americas. Part I, number 4). Field Museum of Natural History Zoological Series volume 13, part 1, number 4. Hellmayr, C.E., and B. Conover. 1949. Catalogue of birds of the Americas. Part I, number 4. Field Museum of Natural History Zoological Series volume 13, part 1, number 4</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Phylogenetic relationships and systematics of a subclade of Mesoamerican emerald hummingbirds (Aves: Trochilidae: Trochilini)). Zootaxa 4748: 581–591. Hernández-Baños, B.E., L.E. Zamudio-Beltrán, and B. Milá. 2020. Phylogenetic relationships and systematics of a subclade of Mesoamerican emerald hummingbirds (Aves: Trochilidae: Trochilini). Zootaxa 4748: 581–591</citation>
                <citation>1996 (Handbook of Australian, New Zealand and Antarctic birds. Volume 3). Oxford University Press, Melbourne. Higgins, P.J., and S.J.J.F. Davies (editors). 1996. Handbook of Australian, New Zealand and Antarctic birds. Volume 3. Oxford University Press, Melbourne</citation>
                <citation>2003 (Birds of Venezuela. Second edition). Princeton University Press, Princeton, New Jersey. Hilty, S.L. 2003. Birds of Venezuela. Second edition. Princeton University Press, Princeton, New Jersey</citation>
                <citation>2014 (McConnell’s Flycatcher Mionectes macconnelli is more than one species). Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 134: 270-279. Hilty, S.L., and D. Ascanio. 2014. McConnell’s Flycatcher Mionectes macconnelli is more than one species. Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 134: 270-279</citation>
                <citation>2005 (Roberts Birds of southern Africa. VII edition). Trustees of the John Voelcker Bird Book Fund, Cape Town. Hockey, P.A.R., W.R.J. Dean, and P.G. Ryan (editors). 2005. Roberts Birds of southern Africa. VII edition. Trustees of the John Voelcker Bird Book Fund, Cape Town</citation>
                <citation>2016 (Avoiding missing data biases in phylogenomic inference: an empirical study in the landfowl (Aves: Galliformes)). Molecular Biology and Evolution 33: 1110-1125. Hosner, P.A., B.C. Faircloth, T.C. Glenn, E.L. Braun, and R.T. Kimball. 2016. Avoiding missing data biases in phylogenomic inference: an empirical study in the landfowl (Aves: Galliformes). Molecular Biology and Evolution 33: 1110-1125</citation>
                <citation>2017 (How do seemingly non-vagile clades accomplish trans-marine dispersal? Trait and dispersal evolution in the landfowl (Aves: Galliformes)). Proceedings of the Royal Society B 284: 20170210. Hosner, P.A., J.A. Tobias, E.L. Braun, and R.T. Kimball. 2017. How do seemingly non-vagile clades accomplish trans-marine dispersal? Trait and dispersal evolution in the landfowl (Aves: Galliformes). Proceedings of the Royal Society B 284: 20170210</citation>
                <citation>1998 (Great Horned Owl (Bubo virginianus)). In A. Poole and F. Gill (editors), Birds of North America. Number 372. Cornell Laboratory of Ornithology, Ithaca, New York. Houston, C.S., D.G. Smith, and C. Rohner. 1998. Great Horned Owl (Bubo virginianus). In A. Poole and F. Gill (editors), Birds of North America. Number 372. Cornell Laboratory of Ornithology, Ithaca, New York</citation>
                <citation>1994 (The specific status of Black-faced Antthrushes in Middle America). Cotinga 1: 21–25. Howell, S.N.G. 1994. The specific status of Black-faced Antthrushes in Middle America. Cotinga 1: 21–25</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Mitochondrial genomes and thousands of ultraconserved elements resolve the taxonomy and historical biogeography of the Euphonia and Chlorophonia finches (Passeriformes: Fringillidae)). Auk 137: ukaa016. Imfeld, T.S., F.K. Barker, and R.T. Brumfield. 2020. Mitochondrial genomes and thousands of ultraconserved elements resolve the taxonomy and historical biogeography of the Euphonia and Chlorophonia finches (Passeriformes: Fringillidae). Auk 137: ukaa016</citation>
                <citation>1988 (Genetic differentiation between North American kinglets and comparisons with three allied passerines). Auk 105: 386–390. Ingold, J. L., L. A. Weigt, and S. I. Guttman. 1988. Genetic differentiation between North American kinglets and comparisons with three allied passerines. Auk 105: 386–390</citation>
                <citation>2006 (Nuclear DNA from old collections of avian study skins reveals the evolutionary history of the Old World suboscines (Aves, Passeriformes)). Zoologica Scripta 35: 567-580. Irestedt, M., J.I. Ohlson, D. Zuccon, M. Källersjö, and P.G.P. Ericson. 2006. Nuclear DNA from old collections of avian study skins reveals the evolutionary history of the Old World suboscines (Aves, Passeriformes). Zoologica Scripta 35: 567-580</citation>
                <citation>2017 (Calls distinguish species of antbirds (Aves: Passeriformes: Thamnophilidae) in the genus Pyriglena). Zootaxa 4291: 275–294. Isler, M.L., and M. Maldonado-Coelho. 2017. Calls distinguish species of antbirds (Aves: Passeriformes: Thamnophilidae) in the genus Pyriglena. Zootaxa 4291: 275–294</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Taxonomic evaluation of the Grallaria rufula (Rufous Antpitta) complex (Aves: Passeriformes: Grallariidae) distinguishes sixteen species). Zootaxa 4817: 1–74. Isler, M. L., R. T. Chesser, M. B. Robbins, A. M. Cuervo, C. D. Cadena, and P. A. Hosner. 2020. Taxonomic evaluation of the Grallaria rufula (Rufous Antpitta) complex (Aves: Passeriformes: Grallariidae) distinguishes sixteen species. Zootaxa 4817: 1–74</citation>
                <citation>2018b (The phylogenetic position of the extinct Cuban Macaw Ara tricolor based on complete mitochondrial genome sequences). Ibis 160: 666-672. Johansson, U.S., P.G.P. Ericson, M.P.K. Blom, and M. Irestedt. 2018. The phylogenetic position of the extinct Cuban Macaw Ara tricolor based on complete mitochondrial genome sequences. Ibis 160: 666-672</citation>
                <citation>2020a (How far east can a Western Whistler go? Genomic data reveal large eastward range extension, taxonomic and nomenclatural change, and reassessment of conservation needs). Emu 121: 90-101. Joseph, L., C.D. Campbell, A. Drew, S.S. Brady, Á. Nyári, and M.J. Andersen. 2020a. How far east can a Western Whistler go? Genomic data reveal large eastward range extension, taxonomic and nomenclatural change, and reassessment of conservation needs. Emu 121: 90-101</citation>
                <citation>2020b (Improved systematics of lorikeets reflects their evolutionary history and frames conservation priorities). Emu 120: 201-215. Joseph, L., J. Merwin, and B.T. Smith. 2020b. Improved systematics of lorikeets reflects their evolutionary history and frames conservation priorities. Emu 120: 201-215</citation>
                <citation>1948 (Notes on some Sumatran birds). Zoologische Mededelingen 29: 311‐326. Junge, G.C.A. 1948. Notes on some Sumatran birds. Zoologische Mededelingen 29: 311‐326</citation>
                <citation>2018 (Phylogeography of the Oenanthe hispanica–pleschanka–cypriaca complex (Aves, Muscicapidae: Saxicolinae): Diversification history of open-habitat specialists based on climate niche models, genetic data, and morphometric data). Journal of Zoological Systematics and Evolutionary Research 56: 408-427. Kakhki, N.A., M. Aliabadian, M.I. Förschler, S.M. Ghasempouri, B.H. Kiabi, L.D. Verde Arregoitia, and M. Schweizer. 2018. Phylogeography of the Oenanthe hispanica–pleschanka–cypriaca complex (Aves, Muscicapidae: Saxicolinae): Diversification history of open-habitat specialists based on climate niche models, genetic data, and morphometric data. Journal of Zoological Systematics and Evolutionary Research 56: 408-427</citation>
                <citation>2002 (Seabird supertrees: combining partial estimates of Procellariiform phylogeny). Auk 119: 88-108. Kennedy, M., and R.D.M. Page. 2002. Seabird supertrees: combining partial estimates of Procellariiform phylogeny. Auk 119: 88-108</citation>
                <citation>2014 (Classification of the cormorants of the world). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 79: 249-257. Kennedy, M., and H.G. Spencer. 2014. Classification of the cormorants of the world. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 79: 249-257</citation>
                <citation>2019 (The phylogenetic placement of the enigmatic Indian Cormorant, Phalacrocorax fuscicollis (Phalacrocoracidae)). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 130: 227–232. Kennedy, M., S.S. Seneviratne, N.J. Rawlence, S. Ratnayake, and H.G. Spencer. 2019. The phylogenetic placement of the enigmatic Indian Cormorant, Phalacrocorax fuscicollis (Phalacrocoracidae). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 130: 227–232</citation>
                <citation>2000 (A guide to the birds of the Philippines). Oxford University Press, New York and Oxford, United Kingdom. Kennedy, R.S., P.C. Gonzales, E.C. Dickinson, H.C. Miranda, Jr., and T.H. Fisher. 2000. A guide to the birds of the Philippines. Oxford University Press, New York and Oxford, United Kingdom</citation>
                <citation>2008 (Rediscovery of a long-lost Charadrius plover from South-East Asia). Forktail 24: 63-79. Kennerley, P.R., D.N. Bakewell, and P.D. Round. 2008. Rediscovery of a long-lost Charadrius plover from South-East Asia. Forktail 24: 63-79</citation>
                <citation>2011 (A macroevolutionary perspective on multiple sexual traits in the Phasianidae (Galliformes)). International Journal of Evolutionary Biology 2011: 423938. Kimball, R.T., C.M. St. Mary, and E.L. Braun. 2011. A macroevolutionary perspective on multiple sexual traits in the Phasianidae (Galliformes). International Journal of Evolutionary Biology 2011: 423938</citation>
                <citation>2021 (A phylogenomic supermatrix of Galliformes (Landfowl) reveals biased branch lengths). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 158: 107091. Kimball, R.T., P.A. Hosner, and E.L. Braun. 2021. A phylogenomic supermatrix of Galliformes (Landfowl) reveals biased branch lengths. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 158: 107091</citation>
                <citation>2009 (A substitute name for Serinus estherae orientalis Chasen). Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 129: 63-64. Kinzelbach, R., E.C. Dickinson, and S. Somadikarta. 2009. A substitute name for Serinus estherae orientalis Chasen. Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 129: 63-64</citation>
                <citation>2020 (The birds of Cuba: an annotated checklist). British Ornithologists&apos; Club checklist 26. British Ornithologists&apos; Club, Tring, United Kingdom. Kirkconnell, A., G.M. Kirwan, O.H. Garrido, A.D. Mitchell, and J.W. Wiley. 2020. The birds of Cuba: an annotated checklist. British Ornithologists&apos; Club checklist 26. British Ornithologists&apos; Club, Tring, United Kingdom</citation>
                <citation>2008 (The birds of Turkey). Christopher Helm, London. Kirwan, G.M., K.A. Boyla, P. Castell, B. Demirci, M. Özen, H. Welch, and T. Marlow. 2008. The birds of Turkey. Christopher Helm, London</citation>
                <citation>2016 (The mistaken manakin: a new genus-group name for Parus pipra Linnaeus, 1758 (Aves: Passeriformes: Pipridae)). Zootaxa 4142: 89-94. Kirwan, G.M., N. David, S.M.S. Gregory, J.A. Jobling, F.D. Steinheimer, and G.R.R. Brito. 2016. The mistaken manakin: a new genus-group name for Parus pipra Linnaeus, 1758 (Aves: Passeriformes: Pipridae). Zootaxa 4142: 89-94</citation>
                <citation>2014 (A comprehensive multilocus assessment of sparrow (Aves: Passerellidae) relationships). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 77: 177-182. Klicka, J., F.K. Barker, K.J. Burns, S.M. Lanyon, I.J. Lovette, J.A. Chaves, and R.W. Bryson, Jr. 2014. A comprehensive multilocus assessment of sparrow (Aves: Passerellidae) relationships. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 77: 177-182</citation>
                <citation>1999 (Owls: a guide to the owls of the world). Yale University Press, New Haven, Connecticut. König. C., F. Weick, and H.-H. Becking. 1999. Owls: a guide to the owls of the world. Yale University Press, New Haven, Connecticut</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Untangling cryptic avian diversity in the High Andes: revision of the Scytalopus [magellanicus] complex (Rhinocryptidae) in Peru reveals three new species). Auk 137: ukaa003. Krabbe, N.K., T.S. Schulenberg, P.A. Hosner, K.V. Rosenberg, T.J. Davis, G.H. Rosenberg, D.F. Lane, M.J. Andersen, M.B. Robbins, C.D. Cadena, T. Valqui, J.F. Salter, A.J. Spencer, F. Angulo, and J. Fjeldså. 2020. Untangling cryptic avian diversity in the High Andes: revision of the Scytalopus [magellanicus] complex (Rhinocryptidae) in Peru reveals three new species. Auk 137:</citation>
                <citation>2011 (Endangered subspecies of the Reed Bunting (Emberiza schoeniclus witherbyi and E. s. lusitanica) in Iberian Peninsula have different genetic structures). Journal of Ornithology 152: 681‐693. Kvist, L., S. Ponnikas, E.J. Belda, I. Encabo, E. Martínez, A. Onrubia, J.M. Hernández, P. Vera, J.M. Neto, and J.S. Monrós. 2011. Endangered subspecies of the Reed Bunting (Emberiza schoeniclus witherbyi and E. s. lusitanica) in Iberian Peninsula have different genetic structures. Journal of Ornithology 152: 681‐693</citation>
                <citation>1986 (A phylogeny of the thirty-three genera in the Empidonax assemblage of tyrant flycatchers). American Museum Novitates 2846. Lanyon, W.E. 1986. A phylogeny of the thirty-three genera in the Empidonax assemblage of tyrant flycatchers. American Museum Novitates 2846</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Molecular phylogenetics and phenotypic reassessment of the Ramphotrigon flycatchers: deep paraphyly in the context of an intriguing biogeographic scenario). Journal of Avian Biology 2020: e02314. Lavinia, P.D., P. Escalante, P.L. Tubaro, and D. A. Lijtmaer. 2020. Molecular phylogenetics and phenotypic reassessment of the Ramphotrigon flycatchers: deep paraphyly in the context of an intriguing biogeographic scenario. Journal of Avian Biology 2020: e02314</citation>
                <citation>1999 (Type specimens of new forms of Lonchura). Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 119: 214-220. LeCroy, M. 1999. Type specimens of new forms of Lonchura. Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 119: 214-220</citation>
                <citation>1997 (Shrikes: a guide to the shrikes of the world). Yale University Press, New Haven, Connecticut. Lefranc, N. 1997. Shrikes: a guide to the shrikes of the world. Yale University Press, New Haven, Connecticut</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Variation in responses to interspecific vocalizations among sister taxa of the Sittidae: imminent extinction of a cryptic species on Grand Bahama Island?). Avian Conservation and Ecology 15: 15. Levy, H.E., and J.A. Cox. 2020. Variation in responses to interspecific vocalizations among sister taxa of the Sittidae: imminent extinction of a cryptic species on Grand Bahama Island? Avian Conservation and Ecology 15: 15</citation>
                <citation>2017 (The conquering of North America: dated phylogentic and biogeographic inference of migratory behavior in bee hummingbirds). BMC Evolutionary Biology 17: 126. Licona-Vera, Y., and J.F. Ornelas. 2017. The conquering of North America: dated phylogenetic and biogeographic inference of migratory behavior in bee hummingbirds. BMC Evolutionary Biology 17: 126</citation>
                <citation>2017 (Sundaland’s east–west rain forest population structure: variable manifestations in four polytypic bird species examined using RAD-Seq and plumage analyses). Lim, H.C., D.F. Gawin, S.B. Shakya, M.G. Harvey, M.A. Rahman, and F.H. Sheldon. 2017. Sundaland’s east–west rain forest population structure: variable manifestations in four polytypic bird species examined using RAD-Seq and plumage analyses. Biogeography 44:2 259–2271. Lim, H.C., D.F. Gawin, S.B. Shakya, M.G. Harvey, M.A. Rahman, and F.H. Sheldon. 2017. Sundaland’s east–west rain forest population structure: variable manifestations in four polytypic bird species examined using RAD-Seq and plumage analyses. Journal of Biogeography 44:2 259–2271</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Colour variation and taxonomy of Picumnus limae Snethlage, 1924 and P. fulvescens Stager, 1961 (Piciformes: Picidae)). Journal of Ornithology 161: in press. Lima, R.D., B.M. Tomotani, and L.F. Silveira. 2020. Colour variation and taxonomy of Picumnus limae Snethlage, 1924 and P. fulvescens Stager, 1961 (Piciformes: Picidae). Journal of Ornithology 161: in press</citation>
                <citation>2013 (Genetic differentiation between migratory and sedentary populations of the Northern Boobook (Ninox japonica), with the discovery of a novel cryptic sedentary lineage). Journal of Ornithology 154: 987–994. Lin, W.-L., L.L. Severinghaus, H.-Y. Tseng, S.-M. Lin. 2013. Genetic differentiation between migratory and sedentary populations of the Northern Boobook (Ninox japonica), with the discovery of a novel cryptic sedentary lineage. Journal of Ornithology 154: 987–994</citation>
                <citation>2017 (A cryptic new species of hummingbird of the Campylopterus largipennis complex (Aves: Trochilidae)). Zootaxa 4268: 1-33. Lopes, L.E., M.F. de Vasconcelos, and L.P. Gonzaga. 2017.  A cryptic new species of hummingbird of the Campylopterus largipennis complex (Aves: Trochilidae). Zootaxa 4268: 1-33</citation>
                <citation>2018 (The striking polyphyly of Suiriri: convergent evolution and social mimicry in two cryptic Neotropical birds). Journal of Zoological Systematics and Evolutionary Research 56: 270-279. Lopes, L.E., A.V. Chaves, M.M. de Aquino, L.F. Silveira, and F.R. dos Santos. 2018. The striking polyphyly of Suiriri: convergent evolution and social mimicry in two cryptic Neotropical birds. Journal of Zoological Systematics and Evolutionary Research 56: 270-279</citation>
                <citation>1981 (The birds of Cameroon: an annotated check‐List). Verhandelingen van de Koninklijke Academie voor Wetenschappen, Letteren en Schone Kunsten van België, Klasse der Wetenschappen number 163. Louette, M. 1981. The birds of Cameroon: an annotated check‐List. Verhandelingen van de Koninklijke Academie voor Wetenschappen, Letteren en Schone Kunsten van België, Klasse der Wetenschappen number 163</citation>
                <citation>2002 (Pheasants, partridges, and grouse). Princeton University Press, Princeton, New Jersey. Madge, S., and P. McGowan. 2002. Pheasants, partridges, and grouse. Princeton University Press, Princeton, New Jersey</citation>
                <citation>2012 (Evolution and biogeography of South American fire-eye antbirds (genus Pyriglena): insights from molecules and songs). Ph.D. dissertation, University of Missouri-St. Louis, St. Louis, Missouri. Maldonado-Coelho, M. 2012. Evolution and biogeography of South American fire-eye antbirds (genus Pyriglena): insights from molecules and songs. Ph.D. dissertation, University of Missouri-St. Louis, St. Louis, Missouri</citation>
                <citation>2019a (Taxonomy, phylogeny and biogeography of African spurfowls Galliformes, Phasianidae, Phasianinae, Coturnicini: Pternistis spp). Ostrich 90: 145-172. Mandiwana-Neudani, T.G., R.M. Little, T.M. Crowe, and R.C.K. Bowie. 2019a. Taxonomy, phylogeny and biogeography of African spurfowls Galliformes, Phasianidae, Phasianinae, Coturnicini: Pternistis spp. Ostrich 90: 145-172</citation>
                <citation>2019b (Taxonomy, phylogeny and biogeography of &apos;true&apos; francolins: Galliformes, Phasianidae, Phasianinae, Gallini; Francolinus, Ortygornis, Afrocolinus gen. nov., Peliperdix and Scleroptila spp). Ostrich 90: 191-221. Mandiwana-Neudani, T.G., R.M. Little, T.M. Crowe, and R.C.K. Bowie. 2019. Taxonomy, phylogeny and biogeography of &apos;true&apos; francolins: Galliformes, Phasianidae, Phasianinae, Gallini; Francolinus, Ortygornis, Afrocolinus gen. nov., Peliperdix and Scleroptila spp. Ostrich 90: 191-221</citation>
                <citation>2018 (Molecular phylogenetics and species limits in a cryptically coloured radiation of Australo-Papuan passerine birds (Pachycephalidae: Colluricincla)). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 124: 100-105. Marki, P.Z., J. Fjeldså, M. Irestedt, and K.A. Jønsson. 2018. Molecular phylogenetics and species limits in a cryptically coloured radiation of Australo-Papuan passerine birds (Pachycephalidae: Colluricincla). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 124: 100-105</citation>
                <citation>2020 (A comprehensive molecular phylogeny of Afrotropical white-eyes (Aves: Zosteropidae) highlights prior underestimation of mainland diversity and complex colonisation history). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 149: 106843. Martins, F.C., S.C. Cox, M. Irestedt, R.P. Prŷs-Jones, and J.J. Day. 2020. A comprehensive molecular phylogeny of Afrotropical white-eyes (Aves: Zosteropidae) highlights prior underestimation of mainland diversity and complex colonisation history. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 149: 106843</citation>
                <citation>1941 (List of New Guinea birds). American Museum of Natural History, New York, New York. Mayr, E. 1941. List of New Guinea birds. American Museum of Natural History, New York, New York</citation>
                <citation>2019 (Ultraconserved elements put the final nail in the coffin of traditional use of the genus Meliphaga (Aves: Meliphagidae)). Zoologica Scripta 48: 411-418. McCullough, J.M., L. Joseph, R.G. Moyle, and M.J. Andersen. 2019. Ultraconserved elements put the final nail in the coffin of traditional use of the genus Meliphaga (Aves: Meliphagidae). Zoologica Scripta 48: 411-418</citation>
                <citation>2014 (Molecular phylogenetics and the diversification of hummingbirds). Current Biology 24: 910-916. McGuire, J.A., C.C. Witt, J.V. Remsen, Jr., A. Corl, D.L. Rabosky, D.L. Altshuler, and R. Dudley. 2014. Molecular phylogenetics and the diversification of hummingbirds. Current Biology 24: 910-916</citation>
                <citation>1980b (The sparrow-hawks (Accipiter) of the Andaman Islands). Journal of the Bombay Natural History Society 77: 371-412. Mees, G.F. 1980. The sparrow-hawks (Accipiter) of the Andaman Islands. Journal of the Bombay Natural History Society 77: 371-412</citation>
                <citation>1986 (A list of the birds recorded from Bangka Island, Indonesia). Zoologische Verhandelingen number 232. Mees, G.F. 1986. A list of the birds recorded from Bangka Island, Indonesia. Zoologische Verhandelingen number 232</citation>
                <citation>2017 (The Australian bird guide). CSIRO Publishing, Clayton South, Victoria, Australia. Menkhorst, P., D. Rogers, R. Clarke, J. Davies, P. Marsack, and K. Franklin. 2017. The Australian bird guide. CSIRO Publishing, Clayton South, Victoria, Australia</citation>
                <citation>2021 (A new, undescribed species of Melanocharis berrypecker from western New Guinea and the evolutionary history of the family Melanocharitidae). Ibis: in press. Milá, B., J. Bruxaux, G. Friis, K. Sam, H. Ashari, and C. Thébaud. 2021. A new, undescribed species of Melanocharis berrypecker from western New Guinea and the evolutionary history of the family Melanocharitidae. Ibis: in press</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Snipe taxonomy based on vocal and non-vocal sound displays: the South American Snipe is two species). Ibis 162: i968-990. Miller, E.H., J.I. Areta, A. Jaramillo, S. Imberti, and R. Matus. 2020. Snipe taxonomy based on vocal and non-vocal sound displays: the South American Snipe is two species. Ibis 162: 968-990</citation>
                <citation>2007 (Notes on Angolan birds: new country records, range extensions and taxonomic questions). Ostrich 78: 55–63. Mills, M.S.L., and W.R.J. Dean. 2007. Notes on Angolan birds: new country records, range extensions and taxonomic questions. Ostrich 78: 55–63</citation>
                <citation>2019 (Species limits in the African Palm Swift Cypsiurus parvus). Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 139: 75-82. Mills, M.S.L., P. Boesman, and N.J. Collar. 2019. Species limits in the African Palm Swift Cypsiurus parvus. Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 139: 75-82</citation>
                <citation>2010 (A preliminary review of the grebes, family Podicipedidae). Pages 125-131 in Systematic notes on Asian birds 74. British Ornithologists&apos; Club Occasional Publications 5. Mlíkovský, J. 2010. A preliminary review of the grebes, family Podicipedidae. Pages 125-131 in Systematic notes on Asian birds 74. British Ornithologists&apos; Club Occasional Publications 5</citation>
                <citation>1968 (A distributional survey of the birds of Honduras). Ornithological Monographs number 7. American Ornithologists&apos; Union. Monroe, B.L., Jr. 1968. A distributional survey of the birds of Honduras. Ornithological Monographs number 7. American Ornithologists&apos; Union</citation>
                <citation>2018 (The role of landscape change and paleoclimatic events in shaping the evolutionary history of the Polioptila gnatcatchers (Passeriformes, Polioptilidae) with emphasis on species associate with open habitats). Journal of Avian Biology 2018: e01692. Moura, C.C. de M., H.F.P. de Araujo, A. Aleixo, M. Wink, and A.M. Fernandes. 2018. The role of landscape change and paleoclimatic events in shaping the evolutionary history of the Polioptila gnatcatchers (Passeriformes, Polioptilidae) with emphasis on species associate with open habitats. Journal of Avian Biology 2018: e01692</citation>
                <citation>2009 (Explosive Pleistocene diversification and hemispheric expansion of a &quot;great speciator&quot;). Proceedings of the National Academy of Science 106: 1863-1868. Moyle, R.G., C.E. Filardi, C.E. Smith, and J. Diamond. 2009. Explosive Pleistocene diversification and hemispheric expansion of a &quot;great speciator&quot;. Proceedings of the National Academy of Science 106: 1863-1868</citation>
                <citation>2013 (Phenotypic divergence among West European populations of Reed Bunting Emberiza schoeniclus: the effects of migratory and foraging behaviours). PLoS ONE 8: e63248. Neto, J.M. L. Gordinho, E.J. Belda, M. Marín, J.S. Monrós, Peter Fearon, and R. Crates. 2013. Phenotypic divergence among West European populations of Reed Bunting Emberiza schoeniclus: the effects of migratory and foraging behaviours. PLoS ONE 8: e63248</citation>
                <citation>2017b (The effects of Pleistocene climate change on biotic differentiation in a montane songbird clade from Wallacea). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 114: 353-366. Ng, N.S.R., P.R. Wilton, D.M. Prawiradilaga, Y.C. Tay, M. Indrawan, K.M. Garg, and F.E. Rheindt. 2017b. The effects of Pleistocene climate change on biotic differentiation in a montane songbird clade from Wallacea. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 114: 353-366</citation>
                <citation>2018 (Are there two species of Graceful Honeyeater in Australia?). Australian Field Ornithology 35: 149–157. Nielsen, L. 2018. Are there two species of Graceful Honeyeater in Australia? Australian Field Ornithology 35: 149–157</citation>
                <citation>1966 (Kritische Bemerkungen über einige südafrikanische Vögel im Museum A. Koenig, Bonn). Bonner zoologische Beiträge 17: 157‐185. Niethammer, G., and H.E. Wolters. 1966. Kritische Bemerkungen über einige südafrikanische Vögel im Museum A. Koenig, Bonn. Bonner zoologische Beiträge 17: 157‐185</citation>
                <citation>1965 (Notes on some non-passerine birds from eastern Ecuador). Breviora 230. Norton, D.W. 1965. Notes on some non-passerine birds from eastern Ecuador. Breviora 230</citation>
                <citation>1972 (Notes on rare and previously unreported birds from Ecuador). Auk 89: 889-894. Norton, D.W., G. Orcés V., and E. Sutter. 1972. Notes on rare and previously unreported birds from Ecuador. Auk 89: 889-894</citation>
                <citation>1998 (Body size effects and rates of cytochrome b evolution in tube-nosed seabirds). Molecular Biology and Evolution 15: 1360--1371. Nunn, G.B., and S.E. Stanley. 1998. Body size effects and rates of cytochrome b evolution in tube-nosed seabirds. Molecular Biology and Evolution 15: 1360--1371</citation>
                <citation>2016 (Population genetic structure of the Magnificent Frigatebird Fregata magnificens(Aves, Suliformes) breeding colonies in the Western Atlantic Ocean). PLoS ONE 11: e0149834. Nuss, A., C.J. Carlos, I.B. Moreno, and N.J.R. Fagundes. 2016. Population genetic structure of the Magnificent Frigatebird Fregata magnificens(Aves, Suliformes) breeding colonies in the Western Atlantic Ocean. PLoS ONE 11: e0149834</citation>
                <citation>2019 (A sympatric pair of undescribed white-eye species (Aves: Zosteropidae: Zosterops) with different origins). Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society 186: 701–724. O&apos;Connell, D.P., D.J. Kelly, N. Lawless, K. O&apos;Brien, F. Ó Marcaigh, A. Karya, K. Analuddin, and N.M. Marples. 2019. A sympatric pair of undescribed white-eye species (Aves: Zosteropidae: Zosterops) with different origins. Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society 186: 701–724</citation>
                <citation>2007 (A molecular phylogeny of the cotingas (Aves: Cotingidae)). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 42: 25–37. Ohlson, J.I., R.O. Prum, and P.G.P. Ericson. 2007. A molecular phylogeny of the cotingas (Aves: Cotingidae). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 42: 25–37</citation>
                <citation>2008 (Tyrant flycatchers coming out in the open: phylogeny and ecological radiation of Tyrannidae (Aves, Passeriformes)). Zoologica Scripta 37: 315–335. Ohlson, J.I., J. Fjeldså, and P.G.P. Ericson. 2008. Tyrant flycatchers coming out in the open: phylogeny and ecological radiation of Tyrannidae (Aves, Passeriformes). Zoologica Scripta 37: 315–335</citation>
                <citation>2020 (A revised classification of the fluvicoline tyrant flycatchers (Passeriformes, Tyrannidae, Fluvicolinae)). Zootaxa 4747: 167–176. Ohlson J.I., M. Irestedt, H. Batalha Filho, P.G.P. Ericson, and J. Fjeldså. 2020. A revised classification of the fluvicoline tyrant flycatchers (Passeriformes, Tyrannidae, Fluvicolinae). Zootaxa 4747: 167–176</citation>
                <citation>2019 (Earth history and the passerine superradiation). Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America 116: 7916-7925. Oliveros, C.H., D.J. Field, D.T. Ksepka, F.K. Barker, A. Aleixo, M.J. Andersen, P. Alström, B.W. Benz, E.L. Braun, M.J. Braun, G.A. Bravo, R.T. Brumfield, R.T. Chesser, S. Claramunt, J. Cracraft, A.M. Cuervo, E.P. Derryberry, T.C. Glenn, M.G. Harvey, P.A. Hosner, L. Joseph, R.T. Kimball, A.L. Mack, C.M. Miskelly, A.T. Peterson, M.B. Robbins, F.H. Sheldon, L.F. Silveira, B.T. Smith, N.D. White, R.G. Moyle, and B.C. Faircloth. 2019. Earth history and the passerine superradiation.  Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America 116: 7916-7925</citation>
                <citation>2020 (A comprehensive phylogeny and taxonomic evaluation of the waxbills (Aves: Estrildidae)). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 146: 106757. Olsson, U., and P. Alström. 2020. A comprehensive phylogeny and taxonomic evaluation of the waxbills (Aves: Estrildidae). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 146: 106757</citation>
                <citation>2018 (Species limits in northern Eurasian taxa of the common stonechats, Saxicola torquatus complex (Aves: Passeriformes, Muscicapidae)). Vertebrate Zoology 68: 199–211. Opaev, A., Y. Red&apos;kin, E. Kalinin, and M. Golovina. 2018. Species limits in northern Eurasian taxa of the common stonechats, Saxicola torquatus complex (Aves: Passeriformes, Muscicapidae). Vertebrate Zoology 68: 199–211</citation>
                <citation>2009 (The Taiwan Firecrest (Regulus goodfellowi) belongs to the Goldcrest assemblage (Regulus regulus s. l.): evidence from mitochondrial DNA and the territorial song of the Regulidae). Journal of Ornithology 150: 205–220. Päckert, M., J. Martens, and L.L. Severinghaus. 2009. The Taiwan Firecrest (Regulus goodfellowi) belongs to the Goldcrest assemblage (Regulus regulus s. l.): evidence from mitochondrial DNA and the territorial song of the Regulidae. Journal of Ornithology 150: 205–220</citation>
                <citation>2011 (The true shrikes (Laniidae) of the world: ecology, behavior and evolution). Pensoft. Panov, E.N. 2011. The true shrikes (Laniidae) of the world: ecology, behavior and evolution. Pensoft</citation>
                <citation>2012 (The White Ibis Eudocimus albus subspecies of South America). Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 132: 128-132. Patten, M.A. 2012. The White Ibis Eudocimus albus subspecies of South America. Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 132: 128-132</citation>
                <citation>2015 (Black-faced Antthrush (Formicarius analis), version 1.0). In T.S. Schulenberg (editor), Neotropical Birds Online. Cornell Lab of Ornithology, Ithaca, New York. Patten, M.A. 2015. Black-faced Antthrush (Formicarius analis), version 1.0. In T.S. Schulenberg (editor), Neotropical Birds Online. Cornell Lab of Ornithology, Ithaca, New York</citation>
                <citation>1970 (Subfamily Emberizinae, buntings and American sparrows. Pages 3-214 in R.A. Paynter, Jr. and R.W. Storer (editors), Check-list of birds of the world. Volume XIII). Museum of Comparative Zoology, Cambridge, Massachusetts. Paynter, R.A., Jr. 1970. Subfamily Emberizinae, buntings and American sparrows. Pages 3-214 in R.A. Paynter, Jr. and R.W. Storer (editors), Check-list of birds of the world. Volume XIII. Museum of Comparative Zoology, Cambridge, Massachusetts</citation>
                <citation>2017 (Characterizing divergence through three adjacent Australian avian transition zones). Journal of Biogeography 44: 2247-2258. Peñalba, J.V., I.J. Mason, R. Schodde, C. Moritz, and L. Joseph. 2017. Characterizing divergence through three adjacent Australian avian transition zones. Journal of Biogeography 44: 2247-2258</citation>
                <citation>2005 (Some taxonomic comments on the genus Polyplectron (Phasianidae)). Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 125: 228‐229. Penhallurick, J., and M. Walters. 2005. Some taxonomic comments on the genus Polyplectron (Phasianidae). Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 125: 228‐229</citation>
                <citation>2004 (Analysis of the taxonomy and nomenclature of the Procellariiformes based on complete nucleotide sequences of the mitochondrial cytochrome b gene). Emu 104: 125-147. Penhallurick, J., and M. Wink. 2004. Analysis of the taxonomy and nomenclature of the Procellariiformes based on complete nucleotide sequences of the mitochondrial cytochrome b gene. Emu 104: 125-147</citation>
                <citation>2016 (Sorting out relationships among the grouse and ptarmigan using intron, mitochondrial, and ultra-conserved element sequences). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 98: 123-132. Persons, N.W., P.A. Hosner, K.A. Meiklejohn, E.L. Braun, and R.T. Kimball. 2016. Sorting out relationships among the grouse and ptarmigan using intron, mitochondrial, and ultra-conserved element sequences. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 98: 123-132</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Cryptic speciation in gentoo penguins is driven by geographic isolation and regional marine conditions: unforeseen vulnerabilities to global change). Diversity and Distributions 26: 958-975. Pertierra, L.R., N.I. Segovia, D. Noll, P.A. Martinez, P. Pliscoff, A. Barbosa, P. Aragón, A. Raya Rey, P. Pistorius, P. Trathan, A. Polanowski, F. Bonadonna, C. Le Bohec, K. Bi, C.Y. Wang-Claypool, D. González-Acuña, G.P.M. Dantas, R.C.K. Bowie, E. Poulin, and J.A. Vianna. 2020. Cryptic speciation in gentoo penguins is driven by geographic isolation and regional marine conditions: unforeseen vulnerabilities to global change. Diversity and Distributions 26: 958-975</citation>
                <citation>1937 (Check-list of birds of the world. Volume III). Harvard University Press, Cambridge, Massachusetts. Peters, J.L. 1937. Check-list of birds of the world. Volume III. Harvard University Press, Cambridge, Massachusetts</citation>
                <citation>1945 (Check-list of birds of the world. Volume V). Harvard University Press, Cambridge, Massachusetts. Peters, J.L. 1945. Check-list of birds of the world. Volume V. Harvard University Press, Cambridge, Massachusetts</citation>
                <citation>1948 (Check-list of birds of the world. Volume VI). Harvard University Press, Cambridge, Massachusetts. Peters, J.L. 1948. Check-list of birds of the world. Volume VI. Harvard University Press, Cambridge, Massachusetts</citation>
                <citation>2000 (A new taxon in the Amazilia viridifrons (Chordata: Aves: Trochilidae) complex of southern Mexico). Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 113: 864-870. Peterson, A.T., and A.G. Navarro-Sigüenza. 2000. A new taxon in the Amazilia viridifrons (Chordata: Aves: Trochilidae) complex of southern Mexico. Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 113: 864-870</citation>
                <citation>1959 (Las subespecies de la Cordoniz de Gambel y el problema de los cambios climaticos en Sonora). Anales del Instituto de Biología, Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México 29: 361‐374. Phillips, A.R. 1959. Las subespecies de la Cordoniz de Gambel y el problema de los cambios climaticos en Sonora. Anales del Instituto de Biología, Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México 29: 361‐374</citation>
                <citation>1966 (Further systematic notes on Mexican birds). Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 86: 125-131. Phillips, A. R. 1966. Further systematic notes on Mexican birds. Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 86: 125-131</citation>
                <citation>1991 (The known birds of North and Middle America. Part II. Bombycillidae; Sylviidae to Sturnidae; Vireonidae). Privately published, Denver, Colorado. Phillips, A.R. 1991. The known birds of North and Middle America. Part II. Privately published, Denver, Colorado</citation>
                <citation>2019 (Two overlooked generic synonyms in the Thraupidae (Aves: Passeriformes)). Zootaxa 4608: 593-594. Piacentini, V.Q., P. Unitt, and K.J. Burns. 2019. Two overlooked generic synonyms in the Thraupidae (Aves: Passeriformes). Zootaxa 4608: 593-594</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Vocal differences among the Barred, Cinereous, and Fulvous owls). Western Birds 51: 122-128. Pieplow, N.D., and A. Spencer. 2020. Vocal differences among the Barred, Cinereous, and Fulvous owls. Western Birds 51: 122-128</citation>
                <citation>2019 (Multi-locus phylogeny of African pipits and longclaws (Aves: Motacillidae) highlights taxonomic inconsistencies). Ibis 161: 781–792. Pietersen, D.W., A.E. McKechnie, R. Jansen, I.T. Little, and A.D.S. Bastos. 2019. Multi-locus phylogeny of African pipits and longclaws (Aves: Motacillidae) highlights taxonomic inconsistencies. Ibis 161: 781–792</citation>
                <citation>1938 (Catálogo das aves do Brasil). Revista do Museu Paulista 12. Universidade de São Paulo, São Paulo. Pinto, O.M. de O. 1938. Catálogo das aves do Brasil. Revista do Museu Paulista 12. Universidade de São Paulo, São Paulo</citation>
                <citation>1948 (Notes on the distribution and taxonomy of Mexican game birds). Condor 50: 113–123. Pitelka, F.A. 1948. Notes on the distribution and taxonomy of Mexican game birds. Condor 50: 113–123</citation>
                <citation>2016 (A checklist of the birds of India). Indian Birds 11: 113-170. Praveen, J., R. Jayapal, and A. Pittie. 2016. A checklist of the birds of India. Indian Birds 11: 113-170</citation>
                <citation>2000 (Ferruginous Pygmy‐Owl (Glaucidium brasilianum). I). In A. Poole and F. Gill (editors), The birds of North America. Number 498. The birds of North America, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Proudfoot, G.A., and R.R. Johnson. 2000. Ferruginous Pygmy‐Owl (Glaucidium brasilianum). In A. Poole and F. Gill (editors), The birds of North America. Number 498. The birds of North America, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania</citation>
                <citation>1960 (Family Pycnonotidae. Pages 221-300 in E. Mayr and J.C. Greenway, Jr. (editors), Check-list of birds of the world. Volume IX). Museum of Comparative Zoology, Cambridge, Massachusetts. Rand, A.L., and H.G. Deignan.1960. Family Pycnonotidae. Pages 221-300 in E. Mayr and J.C. Greenway, Jr. (editors), Check-list of birds of the world. Volume IX. Museum of Comparative Zoology, Cambridge, Massachusetts</citation>
                <citation>2005 (Birds of South Asia. The Ripley guide. Volume 2: attributes and status). Smithsonian Institution and Lynx Edicions, Washington D.C. and Barcelona. Rasmussen, P.C., and J.C. Anderton. 2005. Birds of South Asia. The Ripley guide. Volume 2: attributes and status. Smithsonian Institution and Lynx Edicions, Washington D.C. and Barcelona</citation>
                <citation>2012 (Birds of South Asia. The Ripley guide. Volume 2: attributes and status. Second edition). Smithsonian Institution and Lynx Edicions, Washington D.C. and Barcelona. Rasmussen, P.C., and J.C. Anderton. 2012. Birds of South Asia. The Ripley guide. Volume 2: attributes and status. Second Edition. Smithsonian Institution and Lynx Edicions, Washington D.C. and Barcelona</citation>
                <citation>2002 (Family Bucconidae (Puffbirds)). Pages 102‐138 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and J. Sargatal (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. volume 7. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona. Rasmussen, P.C., and N.J. Collar. 2002. Family Bucconidae (Puffbirds). Pages 102‐138 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and J. Sargatal (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. volume 7. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona</citation>
                <citation>2018 (The valid name of Pycnonotus atriceps—or: AOU vs.ICZN).  Raty, L. 2018. The valid name of Pycnonotus atriceps—or: AOU vs.ICZN</citation>
                <citation>2015 (Classification of the Polytminae (Aves: Trochilidae)). Zootaxa 3957: 143-150. Remsen, J.V., Jr., F.G. Stiles, and J.A. McGuire. 2015. Classification of the Polytminae (Aves: Trochilidae). Zootaxa 3957: 143-150</citation>
                <citation>1996 (Munias and mannikins). Pica Press, Sussex. Restall, R. 1996. Munias and mannikins. Pica Press, Sussex</citation>
                <citation>2006 (Birds of northern South America: an identification guide. Volume 1: species accounts). Yale University Press, New Haven, Connecticut. Restall, R., C. Rodner, and M. Lentino. 2006. Birds of northern South America: an identification guide. Volume 1: species accounts. Yale University Press, New Haven, Connecticut</citation>
                <citation>2020a (A lost world in Wallacea: description of a montane archipelagic avifauna). Science 367: 167-170. Rheindt, F. E., D. M. Prawiradilaga, H. Ashari, Suparno, C. Y. Gwee, G. W. X. Lee, M. Y. Wu, and  N. S. R. Ng. 2020. A lost world in Wallacea: description of a montane archipelagic avifauna. Science 367: 167-170</citation>
                <citation>2020b (A taxonomic and conservation re-appraisal of all the birds on the island of Nias). Raffles Bulletin of Zoology 68: 496-528. Rheindt, F. E., C. Y. Gwee, P. Baveja, T. R. Reasyi, A. Nurza, T. S. Rosa, and Haminuddin. 2020b. A taxonomic and conservation re-appraisal of all the birds on the island of Nias. Raffles Bulletin of Zoology 68: 496-528</citation>
                <citation>2001 (The birds of Ecuador: status, distribution, and taxonomy). Cornell University Press, Ithaca, New York. Ridgely, R.S., and P.J. Greenfield. 2001. The birds of Ecuador: status, distribution, and taxonomy. Cornell University Press, Ithaca, New York</citation>
                <citation>1964 (Subfamily Turdinae, Thrushes. Pages 13-227 in E. Mayr and R.A. Paynter, Jr. (editors), Check-list of birds of the world. Volume X). Museum of Comparative Zoology, Cambridge, Massachusetts. Ripley, S.D. 1964. Subfamily Turdinae, Thrushes. Pages 13-227 in E. Mayr and R.A. Paynter, Jr. (editors), Check-list of birds of the world. Volume X. Museum of Comparative Zoology, Cambridge, Massachusetts</citation>
                <citation>1979 (A comment on Actinodura nipalensis (and waldeni)). Journal of the Bombay Natural History Society 76: 21‐23. Ripley, S.D. 1979. A comment on Actinodura nipalensis (and waldeni). Journal of the Bombay Natural History Society 76: 21‐23</citation>
                <citation>1982 (A synopsis of the birds of India and Pakistan together with those of Nepal, Bhutan, Bangldesh and Srki Lanka). Bombay Natural History Society, Bombay. Ripley, S.D. 1982. A synopsis of the birds of India and Pakistan together with those of Nepal, Bhutan, Bangldesh and Srki Lanka. Bombay Natural History Society, Bombay</citation>
                <citation>2015 (Undiscovered owls). The Sound Approach, Dorset, United Kingdom. Robb, M.S., A.B. van den Berg, and M. Constantine. 2015. Undiscovered owls. The Sound Approach, Dorset, United Kingdom</citation>
                <citation>2014 (Canada to Tierra del Fuego: species limits and historical biogeography of the Sedge Wren (Cistothorus platensis)). Wilson Journal of Ornithology 126: 649-662. Robbins, M.B., and Á.S. Nyári. 2014. Canada to Tierra del Fuego: species limits and historical biogeography of the Sedge Wren (Cistothorus platensis). Wilson Journal of Ornithology 126: 649-662</citation>
                <citation>1922 (Review of the nomenclature of South African birds). Annals of the Transvaal Museum 8: 187-272. Roberts, A. 1922. Review of the nomenclature of South African birds. Annals of the Transvaal Museum 8: 187-272</citation>
                <citation>1998 (Towards a new taxonomy for albatrosses). Pages 13‐19 G. Robertson and R. Gales (editors), The albatross: biology and conservation. Beatty &amp; Sons, Chipping Norton, New South Wales. Robertson, C.J.R., and G.B. Nunn. 1998. Towards a new taxonomy for albatrosses. Pages 13‐19 G. Robertson and R. Gales (editors), The albatross: biology and conservation. Beatty &amp; Sons, Chipping Norton, New South Wales</citation>
                <citation>2011 (When rediscovery is not enough: taxonomic uncertainty hinders conservation of a critically endangered bird). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 61: 949-952. Robertson, B.C., B.M. Stephenson, and S.J. Goldstien. 2011. When rediscovery is not enough: taxonomic uncertainty hinders conservation of a critically endangered bird. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 61: 949-952</citation>
                <citation>1994 (A reappraisal of the taxonomy of the Spotted Bush‐Warbler Bradypterus thoracicus). Forktail 10: 159‐172. Round, P.D., and V.M. Loskot. 1994. A reappraisal of the taxonomy of the Spotted Bush‐Warbler Bradypterus thoracicus. Forktail 10: 159‐172</citation>
                <citation>2019 (Population divergence and gene flow in two East Asian shorebirds on the verge of speciation). Scientific Reports 9: 8546. Sadanandan, K.R., C. Küpper, G.W. Low, C.-T. Yao, Y. Li, T. Xu, F.E . Rheindt, and S. Wu. 2019. Population divergence and gene flow in two East Asian shorebirds on the verge of speciation. Scientific Reports 9: 8546</citation>
                <citation>2013 (The birds of Africa. Volume VIII. The Malagasy region). Christopher Helm, London. Safford, R., and F. Hawkins (editors). 2013. The birds of Africa. Volume VIII. The Malagasy region. Christopher Helm, London</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Extensive paraphyly in the typical owl family (Strigidae)). Auk 137:  ukz070. Salter, J.F., C.H. Oliveros, P.A. Hosner, J.D. Manthey, M.B. Robbins, R.G. Moyle, R.T. Brumfield, and B.C. Faircloth. 2020. Extensive paraphyly in the typical owl family (Strigidae). Auk 137:  ukz070</citation>
                <citation>2011 (Taxonomic recommendations for British birds: seventh report). Ibis 153: 883-892. Sangster, G., J.M. Collinson, P.-A. Crochet, A.G. Knox, D.T. Parkin, L. Svensson, and S.C. Votier. 2011. Taxonomic recommendations for British birds: seventh report. Ibis 153: 883-892</citation>
                <citation>2015 (Patterns of genetic and morphological divergence reveal a species complex in the Plain Wren (Cantorchilus modestus)). Auk 132: 795-807. Saucier, J.R., C. Sánchez, and M.D. Carling. 2015. Patterns of genetic and morphological divergence reveal a species complex in the Plain Wren (Cantorchilus modestus). Auk 132: 795-807</citation>
                <citation>2019 (A distinctive new species of flowerpecker (Passeriformes: Dicaeidae) from Borneo). Zootaxa 4686: 451–464. Saucier, J.R., C.M. Milensky, M.A. Caraballo-Ortiz, R. Ragai, N.F. Dahlan, and D.P. Edwards. 2019. A distinctive new species of flowerpecker (Passeriformes: Dicaeidae) from Borneo. Zootaxa 4686: 451–464</citation>
                <citation>1997 (Aves (Columbidae to Coraciidae). Volume 37.2 in W.W.K. Houston and A. Wells (editors), Zoological Catalogue of Australia). CSIRO Publishing, Melbourne. Schodde, R., and I.J. Mason. 1997. Aves (Columbidae to Coraciidae). Volume 37.2 in W.W.K. Houston and A. Wells (editors), Zoological Catalogue of Australia. CSIRO Publishing, Melbourne</citation>
                <citation>1980 (Variation in the Striated Heron Butorides striatus in Australasia). Emu 80: 203‐212. Schodde, R., I.J. Mason, M.L. Dudzinski, and J.L. McKean. 1980. Variation in the Striated Heron Butorides striatus in Australasia. Emu 80: 203‐212</citation>
                <citation>2012 (Morphological differentiation among the darters). Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 132: 283‐294. Schodde, R., G. Kirwan, and R. Porter. 2012. Morphological differentiation among the darters. Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 132: 283‐294</citation>
                <citation>1999 (Family Trochilidae (hummingbirds)). Pages 468-680 in J. del Hoyo, J., A. Elliott, and J. Sargatal. Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 5. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona, Spain. Schuchmann, K.-L. 1999. Family Trochilidae (hummingbirds). Pages 468-680 in J. del Hoyo, J., A. Elliott, and J. Sargatal. Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 5. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona, Spain</citation>
                <citation>2000 (Biogeography and taxonomy of the Andean genus Haplophaedia Simon (Aves: Trochilidae), with the description of a new subspecies from Ecuador). Ornithologischer Anzeiger 39: 17-42. Schuchmann, K.-L., A.-A. Weller, and I. Heynen. 2000. Biogeography and taxonomy of the Andean genus Haplophaedia Simon (Aves: Trochilidae), with the description of a new subspecies from Ecuador. Ornithologischer Anzeiger 39: 17-42</citation>
                <citation>2003 (Biogeography and taxonomy of Lafresnaya (Trochilide), with a new subspecies from Colombia). Ornitología Neotropical 14: 157-171. Schuchmann, K.-L., A.-A. Weller, and E. Wulfmeyer. 2003. Biogeography and taxonomy of Lafresnaya (Trochilide), with a new subspecies from Colombia. Ornitología Neotropical 14: 157-171</citation>
                <citation>2007 (Birds of Peru). Princeton University Press, Princeton, New Jersey. Schulenberg, T.S., D.F. Stotz, D.F. Lane, J.P. O’Neill, and T.A. Parker III. 2007. Birds of Peru. Princeton University Press, Princeton, New Jersey</citation>
                <citation>2015 (Molecular phylogenetics suggests a New Guinean origin and frequent episodes of founder-event speciation in the nectarivorous lories and lorikeets (Aves: Psittaciformes)). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 90: 34–48. Schweizer, M., T.F. Wright, J.V. Peñalba, E.E. Schirtzinger, and L. Joseph. 2015. Molecular phylogenetics suggests a New Guinean origin and frequent episodes of founder-event speciation in the nectarivorous lories and lorikeets (Aves: Psittaciformes). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 90: 34–48</citation>
                <citation>2018 (Contrasting patterns of diversification in two sister species of martins (Aves: Hirundinidae): the Sand Martin Riparia riparia and the Pale Martin R. diluta). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 125: 116–126. Schweizer, M., Y. Liu, U. Olsson, H. Shirihai, Q. Huang, P.J. Leader, J.Luis Copete, G.M. Kirwan, G. Chen, and L. Svensson. 2018. Contrasting patterns of diversification in two sister species of martins (Aves: Hirundinidae): the Sand Martin Riparia riparia and the Pale Martin R. diluta. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 125: 116–126</citation>
                <citation>2019 (Genome-wide evidence supports mitochondrial relationships and pervasive parallel phenotypic evolution in open-habitat chats). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 139: 106568. Schweizer, M., V.M. Warmuth, N.A. Kakhki, M. Aliabadian, M. Förschler, H. Shirihai, P. Ewels, J. Gruselius, R.-A. Olsen, H. Schielzeth, A. Suh, and R. Burri. 2019. Genome-wide evidence supports mitochondrial relationships and pervasive parallel phenotypic evolution in open-habitat chats. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 139: 106568</citation>
                <citation>2020 (A molecular analysis of the mysterious Vaurie’s Nightjar Caprimulgus centralasicus yields fresh insight into its taxonomic status). Journal of Ornithology 161: 635–650. Schweizer, M., C. Etzbauer, H. Shirihai, T. Töpfer, and G.M. Kirwan. 2020. A molecular analysis of the mysterious Vaurie’s Nightjar Caprimulgus centralasicus yields fresh insight into its taxonomic status. Journal of Ornithology 161: 635–650</citation>
                <citation>2016 (An African origin of the Eurylaimides (Passeriformes) and the successful diversification of the ground-foraging pittas (Pittidae)). Molecular Biology and Evolution 34: 483–499. Selvatti, A.P., A. Galvão, A.G. Pereira, L.P. Gonzaga, and C.A.M. Russo. 2016. An African origin of the Eurylaimides (Passeriformes) and the successful diversification of the ground-foraging pittas (Pittidae). Molecular Biology and Evolution 34: 483–499</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Investigating the utility of traditional and genomic multi-locus datasets to resolve relationships in Lipaugus and Tijuca (Cotingidae)). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution xxx. Settlecowski, A.E., A.M. Cuervo, J.G. Tello, M.G. Harvey, R.T. Brumfield, and E.P. Derryberry. 2020. Investigating the utility of traditional and genomic multi-locus datasets to resolve relationships in Lipaugus and Tijuca (Cotingidae). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution xxx</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Observations on the relationships of some Sundaic passerine taxa (Aves: Passeriformes) previously unavailable for molecular phylogenetic study). Journal of Ornithology 161: 651-664. Shakya, S.B., M. Irham, M.L. Brady, T. Haryoko, Y.S. Fitriana, O. Johnson, M.A. Rahman, N.J. Robi, R.G. Moyle, D.M. Prawiradilaga, and F.H. Sheldon. 2020. Observations on the relationships of some Sundaic passerine taxa (Aves: Passeriformes) previously unavailable for molecular phylogenetic study. Journal of Ornithology 161: 651-664</citation>
                <citation>2005 (Phylogeny of swallows (Aves: Hirundindidae) estimated from nuclear and mitochondrial DNA sequences). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 35: 254–270. Sheldon, F.H., L. A. Whittingham, R. G. Moyle, B. Slikas, and D. W. Winkler. 2005. Phylogeny of swallows (Aves: Hirundindidae) estimated from nuclear and mitochondrial DNA sequences. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 35: 254–270</citation>
                <citation>2018 (Handbook of Western Palaearctic birds). Helm, London. Shirihai, H., and L. Svensson. 2018. Handbook of Western Palaearctic birds. Helm, London</citation>
                <citation>1982 (Woodpeckers of the world). Delaware Museum of Natural History, Greenville, Delaware. Short, L.L. 1982. Woodpeckers of the world. Delaware Museum of Natural History, Greenville, Delaware</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Cryptic and extensive hybridization between ancient lineages of American crows). Molecular Ecology 29: 956-969. Slager, D.L., K.L. Epperly, R.R. Ha, S. Rohwer, C. Wood, C. Van Hemert, and J. Klicka. 2020. Cryptic and extensive hybridization between ancient lineages of American crows. Molecular Ecology 29: 956-969</citation>
                <citation>2013 (Identifying biases at different spatial and temporal scales of diversification: a case study in the Neotropical parrotlet genus Forpus). Molecular Ecology 22: 483-494. Smith, B.T., C.C. Ribas, B.M. Whitney, B.E. Hernández-Baños, and J. Klicka. 2013. Identifying biases at different spatial and temporal scales of diversification: a case study in the Neotropical parrotlet genus Forpus. Molecular Ecology 22: 483-494</citation>
                <citation>2018 (Species delimitation and biogeography of the gnatcatchers and gnatwrens (Aves: Polioptilidae)). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 126: 45-57. Smith, B.T., R.W. Bryson, Jr., W.M. Mauck III, J. Chaves, M.B. Robbins, A. Aleixo, and J. Klicka. 2018. Species delimitation and biogeography of the gnatcatchers and gnatwrens (Aves: Polioptilidae). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 126: 45-57</citation>
                <citation>2001 (Family Momotidae (Motmots)). Pages 264‐284 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and J. Sargatal (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 6. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona. Snow, D.W. 2001. Family Momotidae (Motmots). Pages 264‐284 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and J. Sargatal (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 6. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona</citation>
                <citation>1957 (The avifauna of the Tres Marias Islands, Mexico). Auk 74: 413-432. Stager, K.E. 1957. The avifauna of the Tres Marias Islands, Mexico. Auk 74: 413-432</citation>
                <citation>2011 (Molekulargenetische Untersuchung in der Gruppe der Möwen (Laridae) zur Erforschung der Verwandtschaftsbeziehungen und phylogeographischer Differenzierung). Ph.D. Dissertation. University of Greifswald, Greifswald, Germany. Sternkopf, V. 2011. Molekulargenetische Untersuchung in der Gruppe der Möwen (Laridae) zur Erforschung der Verwandtschaftsbeziehungen und phylogeographischer Differenzierung. Ph.D. Dissertation. University of Greifswald, Greifswald, Germany</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Molecular species delimitation of larks (Aves: Alaudidae), and integrative taxonomy of the genus Calandrella, with the description of a range-restricted African relic taxon). Diversity 12: 428. Stervander, M., B. Hansson, U. Olsson, M.F. Hulme, U. Ottosson, and P. Alström. 2020. Molecular species delimitation of larks (Aves: Alaudidae), and integrative taxonomy of the genus Calandrella, with the description of a range-restricted African relic taxon. Diversity 12: 428</citation>
                <citation>2019 (The generic nomenclature of the Trochilini: a correction). Zootaxa 4691: 195-196. Stiles, F.G., and J.V. Remsen, Jr. 2019. The generic nomenclature of the Trochilini: a correction. Zootaxa 4691: 195-196</citation>
                <citation>2017a (A brief history of the generic classification of the Trochilini (Aves: Trochilidae): the chaos of the past and problems to be resolved). Zootaxa 4269: 396–412. Stiles, F.G., V. de Q. Piacentini, and J.V. Remsen, Jr. 2017a. A brief history of the generic classification of the Trochilini (Aves: Trochilidae): the chaos of the past and problems to be resolved. Zootaxa 4269: 396–412</citation>
                <citation>2017b (The generic classification of the Trochilini (Aves: Trochilidae): reconciling taxonomy with phylogeny). Zootaxa 4353: 401-424. Stiles, F.G., J.V. Remsen, Jr., and J. McGuire. 2017b. The generic classification of the Trochilini (Aves: Trochilidae): reconciling taxonomy with phylogeny. Zootaxa 4353: 401-424</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Alpha taxonomy of Synallaxis stictothorax group (Aves: Passeriformes: Furnariidae): Synallaxis chinchipensis Chapman, 1925 as a valid species, with a lectotype designation). Vertebrate Zoology 70: 319-331. Stopiglia, R., F.A. Bockmann, C.P. de Assis, and M.A. Raposo. 2020. Alpha taxonomy of Synallaxis stictothorax group (Aves: Passeriformes: Furnariidae): Synallaxis chinchipensis Chapman, 1925 as a valid species, with a lectotype designation. Vertebrate Zoology 70: 319-331</citation>
                <citation>1952 (On the birds collected by Pierre Poivre in Canton, Manila, India and Madagascar (1751-1756)). Ibis 94: 499-523. Stresemann, E. 1952. On the birds collected by Pierre Poivre in Canton, Manila, India and Madagascar (1751-1756). Ibis 94: 499-523</citation>
                <citation>1979 (Order Falconiformes. Pages 271-425 in E. Mayr and G.W. Cottrell (editors), Check-list of birds of the world. Volume I, second edition). Museum of Comparative Zoology, Cambridge, Massachusetts. Stresemann, E., and D. Amadon. 1979. Order Falconiformes. Pages 271-425 in E. Mayr and G.W. Cottrell (editors), Check-list of birds of the world. Volume I, second edition. Museum of Comparative Zoology, Cambridge, Massachusetts</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Canada Jay (Perisoreus canadensis), version 1.0). In Birds of the World (P.G. Rodewald, Editor). Cornell Lab of Ornithology, Ithaca, New York. Strickland, D., and H.R. Ouellet. 2020. Canada Jay (Perisoreus canadensis), version 1.0. In Birds of the World (P.G. Rodewald, Editor). Cornell Lab of Ornithology, Ithaca, New York</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Systematics and distribution of the living and fossil small barn owls of the West Indies (Aves: Strigiformes: Tytonidae)). Zootaxa 4830: 544–564. Suárez, W., and S.L. Olson. 2020. Systematics and distribution of the living and fossil small barn owls of the West Indies (Aves: Strigiformes: Tytonidae). Zootaxa 4830: 544–564</citation>
                <citation>2013 (A taxonomic revision of the Subalpine Warbler Sylvia cantillans). Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 133: 240-248. Svensson, L. 2013. A taxonomic revision of the Subalpine Warbler Sylvia cantillans. Bulletin of the British Ornithologists&apos; Club 133: 240-248</citation>
                <citation>2014 (Species coexistence and the dynamics of phenotypic evolution in adaptive radiation). Nature 506: 359–363. Tobias, J. A., C. K. Cornwallis, E. P. Derryberry, S. Claramunt, R. T. Brumfield, and N. Seddon. 2014. Species coexistence and the dynamics of phenotypic evolution in adaptive radiation. Nature 506: 359–363</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Morphology and vocalization support specific status of the Chestnut-headed Chachalaca, Ortalis motmot ruficeps (Wagler, 1830) (Aves; Galliformes; Cracidae)). Papéis Avulsos de Zoologia 60: e20206012. Tomotani, B.M., L.F. Silveira, and J.F. Pacheco. 2020. Morphology and vocalization support specific status of the Chestnut-headed Chachalaca, Ortalis motmot ruficeps (Wagler, 1830) (Aves; Galliformes; Cracidae). Papéis Avulsos de Zoologia 60: e20206012</citation>
                <citation>1958 (Variation in South American Great Horned Owls). Auk 75: 143-149. Traylor, M. A. 1958. Variation in South American Great Horned Owls. Auk 75: 143-149</citation>
                <citation>2017 (The niche and phylogeography of a passerine reveal the history of biological diversification between the Andean and the Atlantic forests). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 112: 107–121. Trujillo-Arias, N., G.P.M. Dantas, E. Arbeláez-Cortés, K. Naoki, M.I. Gómez, F.R. Santos, C.Y. Miyaki, A. Aleixo, P.L. Tubaro, and G.S. Cabanne. 2017. The niche and phylogeography of a passerine reveal the history of biological diversification between the Andean and the Atlantic forests. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 112: 107–121</citation>
                <citation>2019 (Museum genomics reveals the speciation history of Dendrortyx wood-partridges in the Mesoamerican highlands). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 136: 29-34. Tsai, W.L.E., C. Mota-Vargas, O. Rojas-Soto, R. Bhowmik, E.Y. Liang, J.M. Maley, E. Zarza, and J.E. McCormack. 2019. Museum genomics reveals the speciation history of Dendrortyx wood-partridges in the Mesoamerican highlands. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 136: 29-34</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Morphometric and genetic evidence for four species of gentoo penguin). Ecology and Evolution 10: 13836–13846. Tyler, J., M.T. Bonfitto, G.V. Clucas, S. Reddy, and J.L. Younger. 2020. Morphometric and genetic evidence for four species of gentoo penguin. Ecology and Evolution 10: 13836–13846</citation>
                <citation>1986 (The birds of Africa. Volume II). Academic Press, London. Urban, E.K., C.H. Fry, and S. Keith. 1986. The birds of Africa. Volume II. Academic Press, London</citation>
                <citation>1959 (The birds of the Palearctic fauna. Passeriformes). H.F. &amp; G. Witherby Limited, London. Vaurie, C. 1959. The birds of the Palearctic fauna. Passeriformes. H.F. &amp; G. Witherby Limited, London</citation>
                <citation>1965 (The birds of the Palearctic fauna. Non-Passeriformes). H.F. &amp; G. Witherby Limited, London. Vaurie, C. 1965. The birds of the Palearctic fauna. Non-Passeriformes. H.F. &amp; G. Witherby Limited, London</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Multilocus, phenotypic, behavioral, and ecological niche analyses provide evidence for two species within Euphonia affinis (Aves, Fringillidae)). ZooKeys 952: 129–157. Vázquez-López, M., J.J. Morrone, S.M. Ramírez-Barrera, A. López-López, S.M. Robles-Bello, and B.E. Hernández-Baños. 2020. Multilocus, phenotypic, behavioral, and ecological niche analyses provide evidence for two species within Euphonia affinis (Aves, Fringillidae). ZooKeys 952: 129–157</citation>
                <citation>2017 (A phylogenetic test of sympatric speciation in the Hydrobatinae (Aves: Procellariiformes)). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 107: 39-47. Wallace, W.J., J.A. Morris-Pocock, J. González-Solís, P. Quillfeldt, and V.L. Friesen. 2017. A phylogenetic test of sympatric speciation in the Hydrobatinae (Aves: Procellariiformes). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 107: 39-47</citation>
                <citation>2016 (Ancestral range reconstruction of Galliformes: the effects of topology and taxon sampling). Journal of Biogeography 44: 122-135. Wang, N., R.T. Kimball, E.L. Braun, B. Liang, and Z. Zhang. 2016. Ancestral range reconstruction of Galliformes: the effects of topology and taxon sampling. Journal of Biogeography 44: 122-135</citation>
                <citation>2017 (Historical relationships of three enigmatic phasianid genera (Aves: Galliformes) inferred using phylogenomic and mitogenomic data). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 109: 217-225. Wang, N., P.A. Hosner, B. Liang, E.L. Braun, and R.T. Kimball. 2017. Historical relationships of three enigmatic phasianid genera (Aves: Galliformes) inferred using phylogenomic and mitogenomic data. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 109: 217-225</citation>
                <citation>2019a (Genetic, phenotypic and ecological differentiation suggests incipient speciation in two Charadrius plovers along the Chinese coast). BMC Evolutionary Biology 19: 135. Wang, X., P. Que, G. Heckel, J. Hu, X. Zhang, C.-Y Chiang, N. Zhang, Q. Huang, S. Liu, J. Martinez, E. Pagani-Núñez, C. Dingle, Y.Y. Leung, T. Székely, Z. Zhang, and Y. Liu. 2019a. Genetic, phenotypic and ecological differentiation suggests incipient speciation in two Charadrius plovers along the Chinese coast. BMC Evolutionary Biology 19: 135</citation>
                <citation>2019b (Demographic histories and genome-wide patterns of divergence in incipient species of shorebirds). Frontiers in Genetics 10: 919. Wang, X., K.H. Maher, N.Zhang, P. Que, C. Zheng, S. Liu, B. Wang, Q. Huang, D. Chen, X. Yang, Z. Zhang, T. Székely, A.O. Urrutia, and Y. Liu. 2019b. Demographic histories and genome-wide patterns of divergence in incipient species of shorebirds. Frontiers in Genetics 10: 919</citation>
                <citation>1986a (Family Sylviidae, Old World warblers. Pages 3-294 in E. Mayr and G.W. Cottrell (editors), Check-list of birds of the world. Volume XI). Museum of Comparative Zoology, Cambridge, Massachusetts. Watson, G.E., M.A. Traylor, Jr., and E. Mayr. 1986a. Family Sylviidae, Old World warblers. Pages 3-294 in E. Mayr and G.W. Cottrell (editors), Check-list of birds of the world. Volume XI. Museum of Comparative Zoology, Cambridge, Massachusetts</citation>
                <citation>1991 (A new subspecies of the Double-crested Cormorant, Phalacrocorax auritus, from San Salvador, Bahama Islands). Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 104: 356–369. Watson, G.E., S.L. Olson, and J.R. Miller. 1991. A new subspecies of the Double-crested Cormorant, Phalacrocorax auritus, from San Salvador, Bahama Islands. Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington 104: 356–369</citation>
                <citation>2004 (Biogeographic and taxonomic revision of the trainbearers Lesbia (Trochilidae), with the description of two new subspecies). Ornithologischer Anzeiger 43: 115-136. Weller, A.-A., and K.-L. Schuchmann. 2004. Biogeographic and taxonomic revision of the trainbearers Lesbia (Trochilidae), with the description of two new subspecies. Ornithologischer Anzeiger 43: 115-136</citation>
                <citation>1999 (The birds of the Thai-Malay Peninsula. Volume One). Academic Press, London. Wells, D.R. 1999. The birds of the Thai-Malay Peninsula. Volume One. Academic Press, London</citation>
                <citation>2003 (Systematic notes on Asian birds. 36. A preliminary review of the Chloropseidae and Irenidae). Zoologische Verhandelingen 344. Wells, D.R., E.C. Dickinson, and R.W.R.J. Dekker. 2003. Systematic notes on Asian birds. 36. A preliminary review of the Chloropseidae and Irenidae. Zoologische Verhandelingen 344</citation>
                <citation>1986 (The birds of Wallacea (Sulawesi, The Moluccas &amp; Lesser Sunda Islands, Indonesia)). British Ornithologists&apos; Union Check-list number 7. British Ornithologists&apos; Union, London. White, C.M.N., and M.D. Bruce. 1986. The birds of Wallacea (Sulawesi, The Moluccas &amp; Lesser Sunda Islands, Indonesia). British Ornithologists&apos; Union Check-list number 7. British Ornithologists&apos; Union, London</citation>
                <citation>2001 (Family Alcedinidae (kingfishers). Pages 130-2149 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and J. Sargatal (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 6). Lynx Edicions, Barcelona. Woodall, P.F. 2001. Family Alcedinidae (kingfishers). Pages 130-2149 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and J. Sargatal (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 6. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona</citation>
                <citation>2015 (The correct name of the Curl-crested Aracari (Pteroglossus beauharnaisii) and the date of its publication). Wilson Journal of Ornithology 127: 547-549. Wright, R. 2015. The correct name of the Curl-crested Aracari (Pteroglossus beauharnaisii) and the date of its publication. Wilson Journal of Ornithology 127: 547-549</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Species limits in the Elegant Pitta (Pitta elegans) complex from Wallacea based on bioacoustic and morphometric analysis). Avian Research 11: 42. Yue, A.Y., E.Y.X. Ng, J.A. Eaton, and F.E. Rheindt. 2020. Species limits in the Elegant Pitta (Pitta elegans) complex from Wallacea based on bioacoustic and morphometric analysis. Avian Research 11: 42</citation>
                <citation>2015 (Unexpected divergence and lack of divergence revealed in continental Asian Cyornis flycatchers (Aves: Muscicapidae)). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 94: 232-241. Zhang, Z., X. Wang, Y. Huang, U. Olsson, J. Martinez, P. Alström, and F. Lei. 2015. Unexpected divergence and lack of divergence revealed in continental Asian Cyornis flycatchers (Aves: Muscicapidae). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 94: 232-241</citation>
                <citation>1948a (Studies of Peruvian birds. No. 53. The family Trogonidae). American Museum Novitates number 1380. Zimmer, J.T. 1948. Studies of Peruvian birds. No. 53. The family Trogonidae. American Museum Novitates number 1380</citation>
                <citation>1950d (Studies of Peruvian birds.  No. 58.  The genera Chlorostilbon, Thalurania, Hylocharis, and Chrysuronia). American Museum Novitates number 1474. Zimmer, J.T. 1950d. Studies of Peruvian birds. No. 58. The genera Chlorostilbon, Thalurania, Hylocharis, and Chrysuronia. American Museum Novitates number 1474</citation>
                <citation>2003 (Family Thamnophilidae (typical antbirds)). Pages 448-681 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and D. A. Christie (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 8. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona. Zimmer, K.J., and M.L. Isler. 2003. Family Thamnophilidae (typical antbirds). Pages 448-681 in J. del Hoyo, A. Elliott, and D. A. Christie (editors), Handbook of the birds of the world. Volume 8. Lynx Edicions, Barcelona</citation>
                <citation>2009 (Taxonomic status and evolutionary history of the Saxicola torquata complex). Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 52:7 69–773. Zink, R. M., A. Pavlova, S. Drovetski, M. Wink, and S. Rohwer. 2009. Taxonomic status and evolutionary history of the Saxicola torquata complex. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 52:7 69–773</citation>
                <citation>2020 (Type specimens matter: new insights on the systematics, taxonomy and nomenclature of the subalpine warbler (Sylvia cantillans) complex). Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society 190: 314-341. Zuccon, D., J.-M. Pons, G. Boano, G. Chiozzi, A. Gamauf, C. Mengoni, D. Nespol, G. Olioso, M. Pavia, I. Pellegrino, M. Rakovíc, E. Randi, H. Rguibi Idrissi, M. Touihri, M. Unsöld, S. Vitulano, and M. Brambilla. 2020. Type specimens matter: new insights on the systematics, taxonomy and nomenclature of the subalpine warbler (Sylvia cantillans) complex. Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society 190: 314-341</citation>
                    </bibliography>
            </gbif>
        </metadata>
    </additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
